<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Drivers on NTP: Network Time Protocol</title>
    <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Drivers on NTP: Network Time Protocol</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Arbiter 1088A/B GPS Receiver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver11/</guid>
      <description>Author: David L. Mills (mills@udel.edu) Last update: 11-Sep-2010 05:56 UTC   Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.11.u Reference ID: GPS Driver ID: GPS_ARBITER Serial Port: /dev/gpsu; 9600 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: tty_clk   Description This driver supports the Arbiter 1088A/B Satellite Controlled Clock. The claimed accuracy of this clock is 100 ns relative to the PPS output when receiving four or more satellites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arcron MSF Receiver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver27/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 21-Oct-2010 23:44 UTC
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.27.u Reference ID: MSFa / MSF / DCF / WWVB Driver ID: MSF_ARCRON Serial Port: /dev/arcu; 300 baud, 8-bits, 2-stop, no parity Features: tty_clk   Description This driver supports the Arcron MSF, DCF and WWVB receivers. The clock reports its ID as MSFa, MSF, DCF, or WWVB to indicate the time source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Austron 2200A/2201A GPS Receivers</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver10/</guid>
      <description>Author: David L. Mills (mills@udel.edu) Last update: 11-Sep-2010 05:56 UTC   Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.10.u Reference ID: GPS Driver ID: GPS_AS2201 Serial Port: /dev/gpsu; 9600 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: tty_clk   Description This driver supports the Austron 2200A/2201A GPS/LORAN Synchronized Clock and Timing Receiver connected via a serial port. It supports several special features of the clock, including the Input Buffer Module, Output Buffer Module, IRIG-B Interface Module and LORAN Assist Module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bancomm bc635VME Time and Frequency Processor</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver16/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 21-Oct-2010 23:44 UTC
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.16.u Reference ID: BTFP Driver ID: GPS_BANCOMM Bancomm Device: /dev/btfp0 Requires: Bancomm bc635 TFP device module driver for SunOS 4.x/SunOS 5.x   Description This is the clock driver for the Bancomm bc635VME Time and Frequency Processor. It requires the BANCOMM bc635VME bc350VXI Time and Frequency Processor Module Driver for SunOS 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chrono-log K-series WWVB receiver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver32/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 21-Oct-2010 23:44 UTC
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.32.u Reference ID: CHRONOLOG Driver ID: CHRONOLOG Serial Port: /dev/chronologu; 2400 bps, 8-bits, no parity Features: none   Description This driver supports the Chrono-log K-series WWVB receiver. This is a very old receiver without provisions for leap seconds, quality codes, etc. It assumes output in the local time zone, and that the C library mktime() / localtime() routines will correctly convert back and forth between local and UTC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conrad parallel port radio clock</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver35/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 21-Oct-2010 23:44 UTC
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge factors   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.35.u Reference ID: PCF Driver ID: PCF Parallel Port: /dev/pcfclocks/u or /dev/pcfclocku   Description This driver supports the parallel port radio clock sold by Conrad Electronic under order numbers 967602 and 642002. This clock is put between a parallel port and your printer. It receives the legal German time, which is either CET or CEST, from the DCF77 transmitter and uses it to set its internal quartz clock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dumb Clock</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver33/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 21-Oct-2010 23:44 UTC
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.33.u Reference ID: DUMBCLOCK Driver ID: DUMBCLOCK Serial Port: /dev/dumbclocku; 9600 bps, 8-bits, no parity Features: none   Description This driver supports a dumb ASCII clock that only emits localtime at a reliable interval. This has no provisions for leap seconds, quality codes, etc. It assumes output in the local time zone, and that the C library mktime() / localtime() routines will correctly convert back and forth between local and UTC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forum Graphic GPS Dating station</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver37/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.37.u Reference ID: GPS Driver ID: GPS Parallel Port: /dev/fgclocku   Description This driver supports the Forum Graphic GPS Dating station sold by EMR company.
Unfortunately, sometimes FG GPS start continues reporting of the same date. The only way to fix this problem is GPS power cycling and ntpd restart after GPS power-up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generic NMEA GPS Receiver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver20/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 13-Jan-2020 07:12 UTC
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description NMEA Talker IDs The &amp;lsquo;mode&amp;rsquo; byte About distrusting NMEA date stamps Monitor Data Setting up the Garmin GPS-25XL Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.20.u Reference ID: GPS Driver ID: GPS_NMEA Serial Port: /dev/gpsu; 4800 - 115200 bps, 8-bits, no parity Serial Port: /dev/gpsppsu; for just the PPS signal (this is tried first for PPS, before /dev/gpsu) Serial Port: /dev/gpsu; symlink to server:port (for nmead) Features: tty_clk   Description This driver supports GPS receivers with the $GPRMC, $GPGLL, $GPGGA, $GPZDA and $GPZDG NMEA sentences by default.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generic Reference Driver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver8/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 27-Jan-2014 05:31 UTC
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Timecode variables listed by ntpq (8) Supported Devices Operation Hardware PPS support Monitor Data Fudge Factors Making your own PARSE clocks Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.8.u Reference ID: PARSE Driver ID: GENERIC Serial Port: /dev/refclock-u; TTY mode according to clock type PPS device: /dev/refclockpps-u; alternate PPS device (if not available via the serial port)   Description The PARSE driver supports 20 different clock types/configurations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPSD-NG client driver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver46/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 30-Apr-2015 05:53 UTC
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Naming a Device The ‘mode’ word Syslog flood throttle PPS secondary clock unit Clockstats Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.46.u Reference ID: GPSD Driver ID: GPSD_JSON Serial Port: /dev/gpsu as symlink to the true device (not used directly; see below) Features:   Description This driver is a client driver to the GPSD daemon, which over the time became increasingly popular for UN*Xish platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heath WWV/WWVH Receiver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver19/</guid>
      <description>Author: David L. Mills (mills@udel.edu) Last update: 11-Sep-2010 05:56 UTC   Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.19.u Reference ID: WWV Driver ID: WWV_HEATH Serial Port: /dev/heathu; 1200 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: tty_clk Requires: /usr/include/sys/termios.h header file with modem control   Description This driver supports the Heath GC-1000 Most Accurate Clock, with RS232C Output Accessory. This is a WWV/WWVH receiver somewhat less robust than other supported receivers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hewlett Packard 58503A GPS Receiver and HP Z3801A</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver26/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 5-Oct-2005 04:37 UTC
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Fudge Factors   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.26.u Reference ID: GPS Driver ID: GPS_HP Serial Port: /dev/hpgpsu; 9600 baud, 8-bits, no parity, 19200 baud 7-bits, odd parity for the HP Z3801A   Description This driver supports the HP 58503A Time and Frequency Reference Receiver and HP Z3801A GPS Receiver which use HP SmartClock (TM) to implement an Enhanced GPS receiver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hopf GPS/DCF77 6021/komp for Serial Line</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver38/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 21-Oct-2010 23:44 UTC
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Operating System Compatibility O/S Serial Port Configuration Fudge Factors Data Format Questions or Comments   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.38.X Reference ID: hopf (default), GPS, DCF Driver ID: HOPF_S Serial Port: /dev/hopfclockX Serial I/O: 9600 baud, 8-bits, 1-stop, no parity   Description The refclock_hopf_serial driver supports hopf electronic receivers with serial Interface kompatibel 6021.
Additional software and information about the software driver is available from: http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hopf PCI-Bus Receiver (6039 GPS/DCF77)</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver39/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 21-Oct-2010 23:44 UTC
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Operating System Compatibility O/S System Configuration Fudge Factors Questions or Comments   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.39.X Reference ID: hopf (default), GPS, DCF Driver ID: HOPF_P   Description The refclock_hopf_pci driver supports the hopf PCI-bus interface 6039 GPS/DCF77.
Additional software and information about the software drivers as well as the latest NTP driver source, executables, and documentation is maintained at http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IRIG Audio Decoder</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver6/</guid>
      <description>Author: David L. Mills (mills@udel.edu) Last update: 17-Jul-2014 02:17 UTC   Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Technical Overview Monitor Data Fudge Factors   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.6.u Reference ID: IRIG Driver ID: IRIG_AUDIO Audio Device: /dev/audio and /dev/audioctl   Description This driver synchronizes the computer time using the Inter-Range Instrumentation Group (IRIG) standard time distribution signal. This signal is generated by several radio clocks, including those made by Arbiter, Austron, Bancomm, Odetics, Spectracom, Symmetricom and TrueTime, among others, although it is often an add-on option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JJY Receivers</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver40-ja/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver40-ja/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 12-Oct-2017 09:05 UTC
ENGLISH（英語）
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Mode-1 Mode-2 Mode-3 Mode-4 Mode-5 Mode-6 Mode-100 Monitor Data Fudge Factors   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.40.u Reference ID: JJY Driver ID: JJY Serial Port: /dev/jjyu; それぞれのJJY受信機、GPS時計、テレフォンJJYを参照して下さい。   Description このドライバーは、以下の、日本で販売されている JJY受信機、GPS時計と、電話回線による時刻配信サービスをサポートしています。
   Model Mode Language     トライステート TS-JJY01, TS-JJY02 1 日本語   シーデックス JST2000 2 日本語   エコー計測器 LT-2000 3    シチズンTIC JJY-200 4 日本語   トライステート TS-GPSclock-01 5 日本語   セイコー タイム システム TDC-300 6 英語と日本語   テレフォンJJY 100 英語と日本語     Mode-1 NTPの設定 (ntp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JJY Receivers</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver40/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 12-Oct-2017 09:05 UTC
JAPANESE
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Mode-1 Mode-2 Mode-3 Mode-4 Mode-5 Mode-6 Mode-100 Monitor Data Fudge Factors   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.40.u Reference ID: JJY Driver ID: JJY Serial Port: /dev/jjyu; See corresponding receiver   Description This driver supports the following JJY receivers and the GPS clock sold in Japan, and the time service through a telephone line.
   Model Mode Language     Tristate Ltd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KSI/Odetics TPRO/S IRIG Interface</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver12/</guid>
      <description>Author: David L. Mills (mills@udel.edu) Last update: 11-Sep-2010 05:56 UTC   Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.12.u Reference ID: IRIG Driver ID: IRIG_TPRO TPRO Device: /dev/tprou Requires: KSI/Odetics device driver, /usr/include/sys/tpro.h header file   Description This driver supports the KSI/Odetics TPRO and TPRO-SAT IRIG-B Decoder, which is a module connected directly to the SBus of a Sun workstation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magnavox MX4200 GPS Receiver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver9/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 21-Oct-2010 23:44 UTC
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Operating Modes Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.9.u Reference ID: GPS Driver ID: GPS_MX4200 Serial Port: /dev/gpsu; 4800 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: ppsclock (required)   Description This driver supports the Magnavox MX4200 Navigation Receiver adapted to precision timing applications. This driver supports all compatible receivers such as the 6-channel MX4200, MX4200D, and the 12-channel MX9212, MX9012R, MX9112.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motorola ONCORE - The Shared Memory Interface</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/oncore-shmem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/oncore-shmem/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 21-Oct-2010 23:44 UTC
 Table of Contents  Introduction Activating the Interface Storage of Messages in Shared Memory Opening the Shared Memory File Accessing the data Examples   Introduction In NMEA mode, the Oncore GPS receiver provides the user with the same information as other GPS receivers. In BINARY mode, it can provide a lot of additional information.
In particular, you can ask for satellite positions, satellite health, signal levels, the ephemeris and the almanac, and you can set many operational parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motorola Oncore GPS Receiver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver30/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 21-Oct-2010 23:44 UTC
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.30.u Reference ID: GPS Driver ID: ONCORE Serial Port: /dev/oncore.serial.u; 9600 baud, 8-bits, no parity. PPS Port: /dev/oncore.pps.u; PPS_CAPTUREASSERT required, PPS_OFFSETASSERT supported. Configuration File: ntp.oncore, or ntp.oncore.u, or ntp.oncore_u_, in /etc/ntp/ or /etc/.   Description This driver supports most models of the Motorola Oncore GPS receivers (Basic, PVT6, VP, UT, UT+, GT, GT+, SL, M12, M12+T), as long as they support the Motorola Binary Protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MX4200 Receiver Data Format</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/mx4200data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/mx4200data/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 21-Oct-2010 23:44 UTC
 Table of Contents  Control Port Sentences Control Port Input Sentences Control Port Output Sentences   Control Port Sentences The Control (CDU) Port is used to initialize, monitor, and control the receiver. The structure of the control port sentences is based on the NMEA-0183 Standard for Interfacing Marine Electronics Navigation Devices (version 1.5). For more details, please refer to the NMEA-0183 Specification available from the National Marine Electronics Association.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NeoClock4X</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver44/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 21-Oct-2010 23:44 UTC
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Fudge Factors   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.44.u Reference ID: neol Driver ID: NEOCLK4X Serial Port: /dev/neoclock4x-u   Description The refclock_neoclock4x driver supports the NeoClock4X receiver available from Linum Software GmbH. The receiver is available as a DCF77 or TDF receiver. Both receivers have the same output string. For more information about the NeoClock4X receiver please visit http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIST/USNO/PTB Modem Time Services</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver18/</guid>
      <description>Author: David L. Mills (mills@udel.edu) Last update: 12-Oct-2017 08:13 UTC   Table of Contents  Synopsis Description US Phone Numbers and Formats Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.18.u Reference ID: NIST | USNO | PTB | WWVB Driver ID: ACTS_MODEM Serial Port: /dev/actsu; 9600 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: tty_clk Requires: /usr/include/sys/termios.h header file with modem control and a dial-out (cua) device.   Description This driver supports the US (NIST and USNO) and European (PTB (Germany), NPL (UK), etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PPS Clock Discipline</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver22/</guid>
      <description>Author: David L. Mills (mills@udel.edu) Last change: 31-Mar-2014 07:46 UTC   Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.22.u Reference ID: PPS Driver ID: PPS Serial or Parallel Port: /dev/ppsu Requires: PPSAPI signal interface for PPS signal processing.   NOTE: This driver supersedes an older one of the same name. The older driver operated with several somewhat archaic signal interface devices, required intricate configuration and was poorly documented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSTI/Traconex 1020 WWV/WWVH Receiver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver3/</guid>
      <description>Author: David L. Mills (mills@udel.edu) Last update: 11-Sep-2010 05:56 UTC   Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.3.u Reference ID: WWV Driver ID: WWV_PST Serial Port: /dev/wwvu; 9600 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: tty_clk   Description This driver supports the PSTI 1010 and Traconex 1020 WWV/WWVH Receivers. No specific claim of accuracy is made for these receivers, but actual experience suggests that 10 ms would be a conservative assumption.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PTB Modem Time Service</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/tf582_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/tf582_4/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 21-Oct-2010 23:44 UTC
 Several European countries use the following message data format:
Data format 0000000000111111111122222222223333333333444444444455555555556666666666777777777 7 0123456789012345678901234567890123456789012345678901234567890123456789012345678 9 1995-01-23 20:58:51 MEZ 10402303260219950123195849740+40000500 * A B C D EF G H IJ K L M N O P Q R S T U V W XY Z&amp;lsaquo;CR&amp;rsaquo;&amp;lsaquo;LF&amp;rsaquo; A year B month C day D hour E : normally A for DST to ST switch first hour B for DST to ST switch second hour if not marked in H F minute G second H timezone I day of week J week of year K day of year L month for next ST/DST changes M day N hour O UTC year P UTC month Q UTC day R UTC hour S UTC minute T modified julian day (MJD) U DUT1 V direction and month if leap second W signal delay (assumed/measured) X sequence number for additional text line in Y Y additional text Z on time marker (* - assumed delay / # measured delay) &amp;lsaquo;CR&amp;rsaquo;!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PTB Modem Time Service and other European Laboratories Time Services</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver23/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.23.u Reference ID: PTB Driver ID: ACTS_PTB Serial Port: /dev/ptbu; 1200 baud, 8-bits, no parity Requires: /usr/include/sys/termios.h header file with modem control   Description This driver supports the PTB Automated Computer Time Service (ACTS) and is a modified version of the NIST ACTS driver.
It periodically dials a prespecified telephone number, receives the PTB timecode data and calculates the local clock correction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio CHU Audio Demodulator/Decoder</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver7/</guid>
      <description>Author: David L. Mills (mills@udel.edu) Last update: 17-Jul-2014 02:17 UTC   Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Technical Overview Baseband Signal Processing Majority Decoder Autotune Debugging Aids Monitor Data Fudge Factors   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.7.u Reference ID: CHU Driver ID: CHU Modem Port: /dev/chuu; 300 baud, 8-bits, no parity Autotune Port: /dev/icom; 1200/9600 baud, 8-bits, no parity Audio Device: /dev/audio and /dev/audioctl   Description This driver synchronizes the computer time using shortwave radio transmissions from Canadian time/frequency station CHU in Ottawa, Ontario.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radio WWV/H Audio Demodulator/Decoder</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver36/</guid>
      <description>Author: David L. Mills (mills@udel.edu) Last update: 15-Nov-2012 06:42 UTC   Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Technical Overview Baseband Signal Processing Maximum-Likelihood Decoder Master Clock Discipline Station Identification Performance Program Operation Autotune Debugging Aids Monitor Data Fudge factors   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.36.u Reference ID: WVf or WHf Driver ID: WWV_AUDIO Autotune Port: /dev/icom; 1200/9600 baud, 8-bits, no parity Audio Device: /dev/audio and /dev/audioctl   Description This driver synchronizes the computer time using shortwave radio transmissions from NIST time/frequency stations WWV in Ft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RIPE NCC interface for Trimble Palisade</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver43/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 21-Oct-2010 23:44 UTC
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Why this driver? RIPE NCC clock card Monitor Data Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.43.u Reference ID: RIPENCC Driver ID: RIPENCC   Description This is a special driver developed to be used in conjunction with the RIPE NCC clock card in the RIPE NCC Test Traffic Measurements project.
 Why this driver? The reason we created a separate driver for an antenna for which a (vendor supplied) driver already exists is a design decision.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rockwell Jupiter GPS Receiver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver31/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 21-Oct-2010 23:44 UTC
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.31.u Reference ID: GPS Driver ID: JUPITER Serial Port: /dev/gpsu; 9600 baud, 8-bits, no parity.   Description This driver supports at least some models of the Rockwell Jupiter GPS receivers (Jupiter 11, Jupiter-T); they must at least support the Zodiac Binary Protocol.
The driver requires a standard PPS interface for the pulse-per-second output from the receiver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shared Memory Driver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver28/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 8-Aug-2014 19:17 UTC
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Structure of shared memory-segment Operation mode=0 Operation mode=1 Mode-independent post-processing GPSD Clockstats The &amp;lsquo;mode&amp;rsquo; word Fudge Factors Public vs. Private SHM segments Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.28.u Reference ID: SHM Driver ID: SHM   Description This driver receives its reference clock info from a shared memory segment. The shared memory segment is created with owner-only access by default, unless otherwise requested by the mode word for units ≥2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectracom TSYNC PCI</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver45/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver45/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 26-Mar-2012 05:10 UTC
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.45.u Reference ID: one of GPS, IRIG, HVQ, FREQ, ACTS, PPS, PTP, ACT, USR, or LOCL Driver ID: Spectracom TSYNC PCI Driver Port: /dev/tsyncpciu Features: none   Description This driver supports the Spectracom TSYNC PCI receiver.
 Additional Information Reference Clock Drivers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectracom WWVB/GPS Receivers</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver4/</guid>
      <description>Author: David L. Mills (mills@udel.edu) Last update: 11-Sep-2010 05:56 UTC   Table of Contents  Synopsis Description PPS Signal Processing Monitor Data Fudge Factors   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.4.u Reference ID: WWVB Driver ID: WWVB_SPEC Serial Port: /dev/wwvbu; 9600 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: Optional PPS signal processing, tty_clk Requires: Optional PPS signal processing requires the PPSAPI signal interface.   Description This driver supports all known Spectracom radio and satellite clocks, including the Model 8170 and Netclock/2 WWVB Synchronized Clocks and the Netclock/GPS GPS Master Clock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trak 8820 GPS Receiver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver2/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.2.u Reference ID: GPS Driver ID: GPS_TRAK Serial Port: /dev/traku; 9600 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: tty_clk   Description This driver supports the Trak 8820 GPS Station Clock. The claimed accuracy at the 1-PPS output is 200-300 ns relative to the broadcast signal; however, in most cases the actual accuracy is limited by the precision of the timecode and the latencies of the serial interface and operating system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trimble Palisade and Thunderbolt Receivers</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver29/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 13-Sep-2019 08:07 UTC
  Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Operating System Compatibility GPS Receiver GPS Installation O/S Serial Port Configuration NTP Configuration Time Transfer and Polling Run NTP in Debugging Mode Event Logging Fudge Factors Mode Parameter DEFINEs Data Format Pinouts Notes on the Thunderbolt Receiver’s Firmware   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.29.u Reference ID: GPS Driver ID: GPS_PALISADE Serial Port: /dev/palisadeu Serial I/O: 9600 baud, 8-bits, 1-stop, odd parity Serial I/O (Thunderbolt): 9600 baud, 8-bits, 1-stop, no parity Serial I/O (Copernicus II): 38400 baud, 8-bits, 1-stop, no parity   Description The refclock_palisade driver supports Trimble Navigation&amp;rsquo;s Palisade Smart Antenna GPS receiver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TrueTime GPS/GOES/OMEGA/WWV Receivers</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver5/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.5.u Reference ID: GPS, OMEGA, GOES, WWV Driver ID: TRUETIME Serial Port: /dev/trueu; 9600 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: tty_clk   Description This driver supports several models of Kinemetrics/TrueTime timing receivers, including 468-DC MK III GOES Synchronized Clock, GPS- DC MK III and GPS/TM-TMD GPS Synchronized Clock, XL-DC (a 151-602-210, reported by the driver as a GPS/TM-TMD), GPS-800 TCU (an 805-957 with the RS232 Talker/Listener module), OM-DC OMEGA Synchronized Clock, the TL-3 WWV receiver, and very likely others in the same model families that use the same timecode formats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ultralink Clock</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver34/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Model 325 timecode format Model 320 timecode format Model 33x timecode format Fudge factors   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.34.u Reference ID: WWVB Driver ID: ULINK Serial Port: /dev/wwvbu; 9600 bps, 8-bits, no parity Features: none   Description This driver supports the Ultralink Model 325 (replacement for Model 320) RS-232 powered WWVB receiver.
This driver also supports the Model 320, 330, 331, and 332 decoders in both polled or continous time code mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undisciplined Local Clock</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver1/</guid>
      <description>Author: David L. Mills (mills@udel.edu) Last update: 9-May-2014 08:34 UTC   Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.1.u Reference ID: LOCL Driver ID: LOCAL   Description  NOTE: We recommend against using this driver. A much more flexible replacement is described on the Orphan Mode page.
 This driver was intended for use in an isolated network where no external source of synchronization such as a radio clock or modem is available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USNO Modem Time Service</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver24/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Fudge Factors   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.24.u Reference ID: USNO Driver ID: ACTS_USNO Serial Port: /dev/cuau; 1200 baud, 8-bits, no parity Requires: /usr/include/sys/termios.h header file with modem control   Description No information available.
 Fudge Factors  time1 time  Specifies the time offset calibration factor, in seconds and fraction, with default 0.0.
 time2 time  Not used by this driver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zyfer GPStarplus Receiver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/drivers/driver42/</guid>
      <description>Last update: 21-Oct-2010 23:44 UTC
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.42.u Reference ID: GPS Driver ID: Zyfer GPStarplus Serial Port: /dev/zyferu; 9600 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: none   Description This driver supports the Zyfer GPStarplus receiver.
The receiver has a DB15 port on the back which has input TxD and RxD lines for configuration and control, and a separate TxD line for the once-per-second timestamp.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
