<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3-5.93e on NTP: Network Time Protocol</title>
    <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 3-5.93e on NTP: Network Time Protocol</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Kernel Model for Precision Timekeeping</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/kern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/kern/</guid>
      <description>The technical memorandum: A Kernel Model for Precision Timekeeping (PDF) describes an engineering model which implements a precision time-of-day function for a generic operating system. The model is based on the principles of disciplined oscillators using phase-lock loops (PLL) and frequency-lock loops (FLL) often found in the engineering literature. The model implements a hybrid PLL/FLL discipline algorithm implemented in the kernel. The hybrid loop provides automatic time and frequency steering with update intervals from a few seconds to several hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Kernel Programming Interface for Precision Time Signals</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/kernpps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/kernpps/</guid>
      <description>The technical memorandum: A Kernel Programming Interface for Precision Time Signals (PDF) describes a proposed programming interface for external precision time signals, such as the pulse-per-second (PPS) signal generated by some radio clocks and cesium oscillators.
The memorandum argues for a generic capability in the ubiquitous Unix kernel, which could be used for a wide variety of measurement applications, including network time synchronization and experiments involving performance measurement and evaluation of computer networks and transmission systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access Control Options</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/accopt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/accopt/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Access Control Support Access Control Commands   Access Control Support xntpd implements a general purpose address-and-mask based restriction list. The list is sorted by address and by mask, and the list is searched in this order for matches, with the last match found defining the restriction flags associated with the incoming packets. The source address of incoming packets is used for the match, with the 32-bit address being and&amp;rsquo;ed with the mask associated with the restriction entry and then compared with the entry&amp;rsquo;s address (which has also been and&amp;rsquo;ed with the mask) to look for a match.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arbiter 1088A/B GPS Receiver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver11/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.11.u Reference ID: GPS Driver ID: GPS_ARBITER Serial Port: /dev/gps_u; 9600 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: tty_clk   Description This driver supports the Arbiter 1088A/B Satellite Controlled Clock. The claimed accuracy of this clock is 100 ns relative to the PPS output when receiving four or more satellites.
The receiver should be configured before starting the NTP daemon, in order to establish reliable position and operating conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arcron MSF Receiver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver27/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.27.u Reference ID: MSF Driver ID: ARCRON_MSF Serial Port: /dev/arc_u; 300 baud, 8-bits, 2-stop, no parity Features: tty_clk   Description This driver supports the Arcron MSF receiver, and would probably also support the DCF77 variant of the same clock. The clock reports its ID as MSFa to indicate MSF as a source and the use of the ARCRON driver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Austron 2200A/2201A GPS Receivers</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver10/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.10.u Reference ID: GPS Driver ID: GPS_AS2201 Serial Port: /dev/gps_u; 9600 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: tty_clk, ppsclock (required)   Description This driver supports the Austron 2200A/2201A GPS/LORAN Synchronized Clock and Timing Receiver connected via a serial port. It supports several special features of the clock, including the Input Buffer Module, Output Buffer Module, IRIG-B Interface Module and LORAN Assist Module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>authcert - DES validation program</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/authcert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/authcert/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Files   Synopsis authcert
 Description This program verifies whether the DES encryption algorithm is operating correctly in the particular architecture. The program reads a line from the standard input containing a key, plaintext block and the corresponding encrypted ciphertext block, respectively, as in the following
0000000000000000 0000000000000000 8CA64DE9C1B123A7FFFFFFFFFFFFFFFF FFFFFFFFFFFFFFFF 7359B2163E4EDC583000000000000000 1000000000000001 958E6E627A05557B1111111111111111 1111111111111111 F40379AB9E0EC5330123456789ABCDEF 1111111111111111 17668DFC7292532D1111111111111111 0123456789ABCDEF 8A5AE1F81AB8F2DD0000000000000000 0000000000000000 8CA64DE9C1B123A7FEDCBA9876543210 0123456789ABCDEF ED39D950FA74BCC47CA110454A1A6E57 01A1D6D039776742 690F5B0D9A26939Band generates output as in the following</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authentication Options</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/authopt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/authopt/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Authentication Support Authentication Commands Authentication Key File Format   Authentication Support The NTP standard specifies an extension which provides cryptographic authentication of received NTP packets. This is implemented in xntpd using the DES or MD5 algorithms to compute a digital signature, or message digest. The specification allows any one of possibly 4 billion keys, numbered with 32-bit key identifiers, to be used to authenticate an association.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>authspeed - determine authentication delays</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/authspeed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/authspeed/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Options Files   Synopsis authspeed [ -cdm ] [ -n loops ] auth.samplekeys
 Description This program encrypts a test file and determines the authentication delay to use in the NTP configuration file. There are two choices of encryption algorithm, DES Cipher-Block-Chaining (DES-CBC) and Message Digest 5 (MD5).
 Options  -c  Select total cost of encryption. Default is value to use in the authdelay configuration command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building and Installing the Distribution</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/build/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/build/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Building and Installing under Unix Configuration Compilation Installation Additional make Commands Building and Installing Under Windows NT   Following are instructions to build and install the programs in this distribution.
Note that the automatic build process inspects the machine environment and tests for the presence of system header files and the contents of these files to determine if certain features are available. When one or more of these features are present, the code is compiled to use them; if not, no special code is compiled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration Options</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/config/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/config/</guid>
      <description>Basic Configuration Options - the configure utility The following options are for compiling and installing a working version of the xntp3 distribution. In most cases, the build process is completely automatic. In some cases where memory space is at a premium, or the binaries are to be installed in a different place, it is possible to tailor the configuration to remove such features as reference clock driver support, debugging support, and so forth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration Options</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/confopt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/confopt/</guid>
      <description>Configuration Commands  peer address [key key ] [version version] [prefer] [minpoll minpoll] [maxpoll maxpoll] server address [key key ] [version version] [prefer] [mode mode] broadcast address [key key ] [version version] [ttl ttl]  These three commands specify the time server name or address address to be used and the mode in which to operate. The address can be either a DNS name or a IP address in dotted-quad notation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copyright Notice</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/copyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/copyright/</guid>
      <description>The following copyright notice applies to all files collectively called the Network Time Protocol Version 3 Distribution. Unless specifically declared otherwise in an individual file, this notice applies as if the text was explicitly included in the file.
/************************************************************************ ** Copyright (c) David L. Mills 1992, 1993, 1994, 1995, 1996, 1997 ** ** Permission to use, copy, modify, and distribute this software and ** its documentation for any purpose and without fee is hereby ** granted, provided that the above copyright notice appears in all ** copies and that both the copyright notice and this permission ** notice appear in supporting documentation, and that the name ** University of Delaware not be used in advertising or publicity ** pertaining to distribution of the software without specific, ** written prior permission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging Hints for Reference Clock Drivers</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/rdebug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/rdebug/</guid>
      <description>The ntpq and xntpdc utility programs can be used to debug reference clocks, either on the server itself or from another machine elsewhere in the network. The server is compiled, installed and started using the configuration file described in the xntpd page. The first thing to look for are error messages on the system log. If none occur, the daemon has started, opened the devices specified and waiting for peers and radios to come up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Further Information and Bibliography </title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/biblio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/biblio/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Conformance Statement Selected Bibliography   Conformance Statement The Network Time Protocol (NTP) is used to synchronize the time of a computer client or server to another server or reference time source, such as a radio or satellite receiver or modem. It provides accuracies typically within a millisecond on LANs up to a few tens of milliseconds on WANs relative to Coordinated Universal Time (UTC), as provided by a Global Positioning Service (GPS) receiver, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gadget Box PPS Level Converter and CHU Modem</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/gadget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/gadget/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Introduction Circuit Description Files   Introduction Many radio clocks used as a primary reference source for NTP servers produce a pulse-per-second (PPS) signal that can be used to improve accuracy to a high degree. However, the signals produced are usually incompatible with the modem interface signals on the serial ports used to connect the signal to the host. The gadget box consists of a handful of electronic components assembled in a small aluminum box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generic NMEA GPS Receiver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver20/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Setting up the Garmin GPS-25XL Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.20.u Reference ID: GPS Driver ID: GPS_NMEA Serial Port: /dev/gps_u; 4800 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: tty_clk   Description This driver supports GPS&amp;rsquo;s with the $GPRMC NMEA output string. The driver expects the GPS to be set up to transmit a $GPRMC message every second.
The accuracy depends on the GPS used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generic Reference Driver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver8/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description ntpq (8) Timecode Variables Monitor Data Fudge Factors Making your own PARSE clocks Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.8.u Reference ID: PARSE Driver ID: GENERIC Serial Port: /dev/refclock-u; TTY mode according to clock type Features: ppsclock   Description The timecode of these receivers is sampled via a STREAMS module in the kernel (The STREAMS module has been designed for use with SUN Systems under SunOS 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heath WWV/WWVH Receiver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver19/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.19.u Reference ID: WWV Driver ID: WWV_HEATH Serial Port: /dev/heath_u; 1200 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: tty_clk Requires: /usr/include/sys/termios.h header file with modem control   Description This driver supports the Heath GC-1000 Most Accurate Clock, with RS232C Output Accessory. This is a WWV/WWVH receiver somewhat less robust than other supported receivers. Its claimed accuracy is 100 ms when actually synchronized to the broadcast signal, but this doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen even most of the time, due to propagation conditions, ambient noise sources, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hewlett Packard 58503A GPS Receiver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver26/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.26.u Reference ID: GPS Driver ID: GPS_HP Serial Port: /dev/hpgps_u; 9600 baud, 8-bits, no parity   Description This driver supports the HP 58503A Time and Frequency Reference Receiver. It uses HP SmartClock (TM) to implement an Enhanced GPS receiver. The receiver accuracy when locked to GPS in normal operation is better than 1 usec. The accuracy when operating in holdover is typically better than 10 us per day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hints and Kinks</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/hints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/hints/</guid>
      <description>This is an index for a set of troubleshooting notes contained in individual text files in the ./hints directory. They were supplied by various volunteers in the form of mail messages, patches or just plain word of mouth. Each note applies to a specific computer and operating system and gives information found useful in setting up the xntp3 distribution or site configuration. The notes are very informal and subject to errors; no attempt has been made to verify the accuracy of the information contained in them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build new PARSE clocks</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/parsenew/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/parsenew/</guid>
      <description>Here is an attempt to sketch out what you need to do in order to add another clock to the parse driver: Currently the implementation is being cleaned up - so not all information in here is completely correct. Refer to the included code where in doubt.
 Prerequisites:
 Does the system you want the clock connect to have the include files termio.h or termios.h ? (You need that for the parse driver)  What to do:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write a Reference Clock Driver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/howto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/howto/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Description Files Which Need to be Changed Interface Routine Overview   Description Reference clock support maintains the fiction that the clock is actually an ordinary peer in the NTP tradition, but operating at a synthetic stratum of zero. The entire suite of algorithms used to filter the received data, select the best clocks or peers and combine them to produce a local clock correction are operative as with ordinary NTP peers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IRIG Audio Decoder</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver6/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.6.u Reference ID: IRIG Driver ID: IRIG_AUDIO Audio Device: /dev/irigu Requires: modified SunOS 4.1.3 BSD audio driver and /usr/include/sys/bsd_audioirig.h header file   Description This driver supports the Inter-Range Instrumentation Group standard time-distribution signal IRIG-B using the audio codec native to the Sun SPARCstation. This signal is generated by several radio clocks, including those made by Austron, TrueTime, Odetics and Spectracom, among others, although it is generally an add-on option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IRIG Support Using Sun SPARC Audio</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/irig/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/irig/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Introduction Programming Interface Programming Example Implementation and Configuration Notes   Introduction A companion software distribution bsd_audio.tar.Z includes modifications to the BSD audio driver for the Sun SPARCstation written by Van Jacobson and collaborators at Lawrence Berkeley National Laboratory. The modifications provide for the connection of a standard Inter-Range Instrumentation Group (IRIG) timecode signal generator and the decoding of the signal to produce data sufficient to synchronize a host clock to the IRIG signal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KSI/Odetics TPRO/S IRIG Interface</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver12/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.12.u Reference ID: IRIG Driver ID: IRIG_TPRO TPRO Device: /dev/tpro_u Requires: KSI/Odetics device driver, /usr/include/sys/tpro.h header file   Description This driver supports the KSI/Odetics TPRO and TPRO-SAT IRIG-B Decoder, which is a module connected directly to the SBus of a Sun workstation. The module works with the IRIG-B signal generated by several radio clocks, including those made by Arbiter, Austron, Odetics, Spectracom and TrueTime, among others, although it is generally an add- on option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Line Disciplines and Streams Modules</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/ldisc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/ldisc/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Description How to Use the tty_clk Line Discipline How to Use the tty_chu Line Discipline How to Use the ppsclock Stream Module TIOCDCDTIMESTAMP timestamping   Description Most radio and modem clocks used for a primary (stratum-1) NTP server utilize serial ports operating at speeds of 9600 baud or greater. The timing jitter contributed by the serial port hardware and software driver can accumulate to several milliseconds on a typical Unix workstation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magnavox MX4200 GPS Receiver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver9/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Operating Modes Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.9.u Reference ID: GPS Driver ID: GPS_MX4200 Serial Port: /dev/gps_u; 4800 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: ppsclock (required)   Description This driver supports the Magnavox MX 4200 Navigation Receiver adapted to precision timing applications. It requires the ppsclock line discipline or streams module described in the Line Disciplines and Streams Drivers page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>md5 - generate message digest</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/md5cert/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/md5cert/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Options   Synopsis md5 [ -0123456789 ] [ -h] file
 Description This program generates the message digest of the given file using the RSA Message Digest 5 (MD5) and other selected algorithms. If file is not given, the program uses the standard input.
 Options  -0123456789  Select algorithm from the following list:
     Option Algorithm     -0 null   -1 MD5   -2 SNEFRU   -3 CRC32   -4 CRC16   -5 MD4   -6 MD2   -7 SHA   -8 HAVAL   -9 null     -h  Display the result in hex; the default is base-64.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miscellaneous Options</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/miscopt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/miscopt/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Miscellaneous Commands Variables   Miscellaneous Commands  broadcastdelay seconds  The broadcast and multicast modes require a special calibration to determine the network delay between the local and remote servers. Ordinarily, this is done automatically by the initial protocol exchanges between the local and remote servers. In some cases, the calibration procedure may fail due to network or server access controls, for example. This command specifies the default delay to be used under these circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitigation Rules and the prefer Keyword</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/prefer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/prefer/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Introduction The prefer Peer Peer Classification Mitigation Rules Using the Pulse-per-Second (PPS) Signal Using the Kernel Discipline   Introduction The mechanics of the NTP algorithms which select the best data sample from each available peer and the best subset of the peer population have been finely crafted to resist network jitter, faults in the network or peer operations, and to deliver the best possible accuracy. Most of the time these algorithms do a good job without requiring explicit manual tailoring of the configuration file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Options</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/monopt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/monopt/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Monitoring Support Monitoring Commands   Monitoring Support xntpd includes a comprehensive monitoring facility suitable for continuous, long term recording of server and client timekeeping performance. See the statistics command below for a listing and example of each type of statistics currently supported. Statistic files are managed using file generation sets and scripts in the ./scripts directory of this distribution. Using these facilities and Unix cron jobs, the data can be automatically summarized and archived for retrospective analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIST Modem Time Service</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver18/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Call Management Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.18.u Reference ID: ACTS Driver ID: NIST_ACTS Serial Port: /dev/acts_u; 1200 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: tty_clk Requires: /usr/include/sys/termios.h header file with modem control   Description This driver supports the NIST Automated Computer Time Service (ACTS). It periodically dials a prespecified telephone number, receives the NIST timecode data and calculates the local clock correction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Configuring NTP and Setting up a NTP Subnet</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/notes/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Introduction How NTP Works Configuring Your Subnet Configuring Your Server or Client Xntp3 Versus Previous Versions Traffic Monitoring Address-and-Mask Restrictions Authentication Query Programs Run-Time Reconfiguration Name Resolution Dealing with Frequency Tolerance Violations Tuning Your Subnet Provisions for Leap Seconds and Accuracy Metrics Clock Support Overview Towards the Ultimate Tick Parting Shots  Introduction This document is a collection of notes concerning the use of xntpd and related programs, and on coping with the Network Time Protocol (NTP) in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NTP Debugging Techniques</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/debug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/debug/</guid>
      <description>Once the NTP software distribution has been compiled and installed and the configuration file constructed, the next step is to verify correct operation and fix any bugs that may result. Usually, the command line that starts the daemon is included in the system startup file, so it is executed only at system boot time; however, the daemon can be stopped and restarted from root at any time. Usually, no command-line arguments are required, unless special actions described in the xntpd.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NTP PARSE clock data formats</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/parsedata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/parsedata/</guid>
      <description>The parse driver currently supports several clocks with different query mechanisms. In order for you to find a sample that might be similar to a clock you might want to integrate into parse I&amp;rsquo;ll sum up the major features of the clocks (this information is distributed in the parse/clk_*.c and ntpd/refclock_parse.c files).
 Table of Contents  Meinberg clocks Raw DCF77 Data via serial line DCF77 raw time code Schmid clock Trimble SV6 ASCII time code (TAIP) ELV DCF7000 HOPF 6021 und Kompatible Diem Computime Clock WHARTON 400A Series Clock with a 404.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntpdate - set the date and time via NTP</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/ntpdate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/ntpdate/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Command Line Options Files Bugs   Synopsis ntpdate [ -bBdoqsuv ] [ -a key ] [ -e authdelay ] [ -k keyfile ] [ -o version ] [ -p samples ] [ -t timeout ] server [ &amp;hellip; ]
 Description ntpdate sets the local date and time by polling the Network Time Protocol (NTP) server(s) given as the server arguments to determine the correct time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntpq - standard NTP query program</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/ntpq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/ntpq/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Internal Commands Control Message Commands Bugs   Synopsis ntpq [-inp] [-c command] [host] [&amp;hellip;]
 Description ntpq is used to query NTP servers which implement the recommended NTP mode 6 control message format about current state and to request changes in that state. The program may be run either in interactive mode or controlled using command line arguments. Requests to read and write arbitrary variables can be assembled, with raw and pretty-printed output options being available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntptime - read kernel time variables</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/ntptime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/ntptime/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Options   Synopsis ntptime [ -chr ] [ -e est_error ] [ -f frequency ] [ -m max_error ] [ -o offset ] [ -s status ] [ -t time_constant]
 Description This program is useful only with special kernels described in the A Kernel Model for Precision Timekeeping page. It reads and displays time-related kernel variables using the ntp_gettime() system call. A similar display can be obtained using the xntpdc program and kerninfo command.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntptrace - trace a chain of NTP servers back to the primary source</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/ntptrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/ntptrace/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Options Bugs   Synopsis ntptrace [ -vdn ] [ -r retries ] [ -t timeout ] [ server ]
 Description ntptrace determines where a given Network Time Protocol (NTP) server gets its time from, and follows the chain of NTP servers back to their master time source. If given no arguments, it starts with localhost. Here is an example of the output from ntptrace:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patching Procedures</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/patches/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/patches/</guid>
      <description>A distribution so widely used as this one eventually develops numerous barnacles as the result of porting to new systems, idiosyncratic new features and just plain bugs. In order to help keep order and make maintenance bearable, we ask that proposed changes to the distribution be submitted in the following form.
  Please submit patches in the form of either unified-diffs (diff -u) or context-diffs (diff -c).
  Please include the output from config.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Porting Hints</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/porting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/porting/</guid>
      <description>NOTEThe following procedures have been replaced by GNU automake and autoconfigure. This page is to be updated in the next release.Porting to a new machine or operating system ordinarily requires updating the ./machines directory and the ./compilers directories in order to define the build environment and autoconfigure means. You will probably have to modify the ntp_machines.h file and l_stdlib.h files as well. The two most famous trouble spots are the I/O code in .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PPS Clock Discipline</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver22/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.22.u Reference ID: ATOM Driver ID: ATOM-PPS Serial Port: /dev/pps_u; 9600 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: tty_clk, ppsclock   Description This driver furnishes an interface for pulse-per-second (PPS) signals produced by a cesium clock, radio clock or related equipment. It can be used to remove accumulated jitter and retime a secondary server when synchronized to a primary server over a congested, wide-area network and before redistributing the time to local clients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PTB Modem Time Service</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver23/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.23.u Reference ID: TPTB Driver ID: PTP-ACTS Serial Port: /dev/ptb_u; 1200 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: none Requires: /usr/include/sys/termios.h header file with modem control   Description No further information available.
 Monitor Data When enabled by the flag4 fudge flag, every received timecode is written as-is to the clockstats file.
 Fudge Factors  time1 time  Specifies the time offset calibration factor, in seconds and fraction, with default 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulse-Per-Second (PPS) Signal Interfacing</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/pps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/pps/</guid>
      <description>Some radio clocks and related timekeeping gear have a pulse-per-second (PPS) signal that can be used to discipline the local clock oscillator to a high degree of precision, typically to the order less than 50 us in time and 0.1 PPM in frequency. The PPS signal can be connected in either of two ways: via the data leads of a serial port or via the modem control leads. Either way requires conversion of the PPS signal, usually at TTL levels, to RS232 levels, which can be done using a circuit such as described in the Gadget Box PPS Level Converter and CHU Modem page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference Clock Drivers</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/refclock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/refclock/</guid>
      <description>Reference Clock Drivers Support for most of the commonly available radio and modem clocks is included in the default configuration of the NTP daemon for Unix xntpd. Individual clocks can be activated by configuration file commands, specifically the server and fudge commands described in the xntpd program manual page. The following discussion presents Information on how to select and configure the device drivers in a running Unix system.
Radio and modem clocks by convention have addresses in the form 127.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference Clock Options</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/clockopt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/clockopt/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Reference Clock Support Reference Clock Commands   Reference Clock Support The NTP Version 3 daemon currently supports several different radio, satellite and modem reference clocks plus a special pseudo-clock used for backup or when no other clock source is available. Detailed descriptions of individual device drivers and options can be found in the Reference Clock Drivers page. Additional information can be found in the pages referenced there, including the Debugging Hints for Reference Clock Drivers and How To Write a Reference Clock Driver pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/release/</guid>
      <description>The following changes are in the version 3-5.85 distribution relative to the previous 3.5f version.
  The automatic build procedure has been replaced with GNU autoconfigure. This should make porting to nonstandard machines and operating systems much easier and should simplify the maintenance for multi-architecture sites. See the ./WHERE-TO- START/, ./INSTALL and ./README files for a brief overview of the new building and installing procedures. See the building and installing pages in the HTML documentation for further information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scratchbuilt CHU Receiver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver7/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.7.u Reference ID: CHU Driver ID: CHU Modem Port: /dev/chu_u; 300 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: chu_clk   Description This driver supports a shortwave receiver and special modem circuitry described in the ./gadget directory of the xntp3 distribution. It requires the chu_clk line discipline or streams module described in the Line Disciplines and Streams Drivers page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shared Memory Driver</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver28/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Structure of shared memory-segment Operation mode=0 Operation mode=1 Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.28.u Reference ID: SHM Driver ID: SHM   Description This driver receives its reference clock info from a shared memory-segment. The shared memory-segment is created with owner-only access for unit 0 and 1, and world access for unit 2 and 3.
 Structure of shared memory-segment struct shmTime {int mode; /* 0 - if valid set* use values, * clear valid* 1 - if valid set * if count before and after read of * values is equal,* use values * clear valid*/int count;time_t clockTimeStampSec; /* external clock */int clockTimeStampUSec; /* external clock */time_t receiveTimeStampSec; /* internal clock, when external value was received */int receiveTimeStampUSec; /* internal clock, when external value was received */int leap;int precision;int nsamples;int valid;int dummy[10]; }; Operation mode=0 When the poll-method of the driver is called, the valid-flag of the shared memory-segment is checked:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spectracom8170 and Netclock/2 WWVB Receivers</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver4/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.4.u Reference ID: WWVB Driver ID: WWVB_SPEC Serial Port: /dev/wwvb_u; 9600 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: tty_clk   Description This driver supports the Spectracom Model 8170 and Netclock/2 WWVB Synchronized Clock. This clock has proven a reliable source of time, except in some cases of high ambient conductive RF interference. The claimed accuracy of the clock is 100 usec relative to the broadcast signal; however, in most cases the actual accuracy is limited by the precision of the timecode and the latencies of the serial interface and operating system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tickadj - set time-related kernel variables</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/tickadj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/tickadj/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Command Line Options Files Bugs   Synopsis tickadj [ -Aqs ] [ -a tickadj ] [ -t tick ]
 Description The tickadj program reads, and optionally modifies, several timekeeping-related variables in the running kernel, via /dev/kmem. The particular variables it is concerned with are tick, which is the number of microseconds added to the system time for a clock interrupt, tickadj, which sets the slew rate and resolution used by the adjtime system call, and dosynctodr, which indicates to the kernels on some machines whether they should internally adjust the system clock to keep it in line with time-of-day clock or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time and Time Interval Measurement with Application to Computer and Network Performance Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/measure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/measure/</guid>
      <description>The technical memorandum: Time and Time Interval Measurement with Application to Computer and Network Performance Evaluation (PDF) describes a number of techniques for conducting experiments typical of computer network and transmission systems engineering.
In most experiments in which time is involved, it is necessary to develop estimates of time, frequency and measurement errors from a series of time measurements between the clocks of a number of computers and ancillary devices interconnected by some kind of computer network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TrueTime GPS/GOES/OMEGA Receivers</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver5/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.5.u Reference ID: GPS, OMEGA, GOES Driver ID: TRUETIME Serial Port: /dev/true_u; 9600 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: tty_clk   Description This driver supports several models of Kinemetrics/TrueTime timing receivers, including 468-DC MK III GOES Synchronized Clock, GPS- DC MK III and GPS/TM-TMD GPS Synchronized Clock, XL-DC (a 151-602-210, reported by the driver as a GPS/TM-TMD), GPS-800 TCU (an 805-957 with the RS232 Talker/Listener module), OM-DC OMEGA Synchronized Clock, and very likely others in the same model families that use the same timecode formats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undisciplined Local Clock</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver1/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors Additional Information   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.1.u Reference ID: LCL Driver ID: LOCAL   Description This is a hack to allow a machine to use its own system clock as a reference clock, i.e., to free-run using no outside clock discipline source. This is useful if NTP is to be used in an isolated environment with no radio clock or NIST modem available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USNO Modem Time Service</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/driver24/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Monitor Data Fudge Factors   Synopsis  Address: 127.127.24.u Reference ID: USNO Driver ID: ACTS_USNO Serial Port: /dev/cua_u; 1200 baud, 8-bits, no parity Features: none Requires: /usr/include/sys/termios.h header file with modem control   Description No information available.
 Monitor Data When enabled by the flag4 fudge flag, every received timecode is written as-is to the clockstats file.
 Fudge Factors  time1 time  Specifies the time offset calibration factor, in seconds and fraction, with default 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>xntpd - Network Time Protocol (NTP) daemon</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/xntpd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/xntpd/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Command Line Options The Configuration File Files Bugs   Synopsis xntpd [ -aAbdm ] [ -c conffile ] [ -f driftfile ] [ -k keyfile ] [ -l logfile ] [ -p pidfile ] [ -r broadcastdelay ] [ -s statsdir ] [ -t key ] [ -v variable ] [ -V variable ]
 Description xntpd is an operating system daemon which sets and maintains the system time-of-day in synchronism with Internet standard time servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>xntpdc - special NTP query program</title>
      <link>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/xntpdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://doc.ntp.org/archives/3-5.93e/xntpdc/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Command Line Options Interactive Commands Control Message Commands Runtime Configuration Requests Bugs   Synopsis xntpdc [ -ilnps ] [ -c command ] [ host ] [ &amp;hellip; ]
 Description xntpdc is used to query the xntpd daemon about its current state and to request changes in that state. The program may be run either in interactive mode or controlled using command line arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
