<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>4.1.1 on NTP: Network Time Protocol</title>
    <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 4.1.1 on NTP: Network Time Protocol</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Access Control Options</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/accopt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/accopt/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
The skunk watches for intruders and sprays.
 Table of Contents  Access Control Support The Kiss-of-Death Packet Access Control Commands   Access Control Support ntpd implements a general purpose address-and-mask based restriction list. The list is sorted by address and by mask, and the list is searched in this order for matches, with the last match found defining the restriction flags associated with the incoming packets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association Management</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/assoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/assoc/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
Make sure who your friends are.
 Table of Contents  Association Modes Client/Server Mode Symmetric Active/Passive Mode Broadcast Mode IP Multicast Support Multicasting Manycasting Burst Modes   Association Modes NTP Version 4 (NTPv4) incorporates new features and refinements to the NTP Version 3 (NTPv3) algorithms; however, it continues the tradition of backwards compatibility with older versions. A number of new operating modes for automatic server discovery and improved accuracy in occasionally connected networks are provided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authentication Options</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/authopt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/authopt/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
Our resident cryptographer; now you see him, now you don&amp;rsquo;t.
 Table of Contents  Authentication Support Symmetric Key Scheme Public Key Scheme Leapseconds Table Key Management Authentication Commands Files Bugs   Authentication Support Authentication support allows the NTP client to verify that the server is in fact known and trusted and not an intruder intending accidentally or on purpose to masquerade as that server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building and Installing the Distribution</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/build/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/build/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
For putting out compiler fires.
 Table of Contents  Building and Installing the Distribution Building and Installing under Unix Compilation Installation Configuration If You Have Problems Additional make Commands Building and Installing Under Windows NT   Building and Installing the Distribution As a practical matter, every computer architecture and operating system version seems to be different than any other. The device drivers may be different, the input/output system may be idiosyncratic and the libraries may have different semantics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration Options</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/config/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/config/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
Gnu autoconfigure tools are in the backpack.
 Table of Contents  Basic Configuration Options - the configure utility Options Directory and File Names Host Type Optional Packages Optional Features Radio Clocks PARSE Clocks   Basic Configuration Options - the configure utility The following options are for compiling and installing a working version of the NTP distribution. In most cases, the build process is completely automatic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration Options</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/confopt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/confopt/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
The chicken is getting configuration advice.
 Table of Contents  Configuration Commands Options Auxiliary Commands Bugs   Following is a description of the configuration commands in NTPv4. These commands have the same basic functions as in NTPv3 and in some cases new functions and new arguments. There are two classes of commands, configuration commands that configure a persistent association with a remote server, peer or reference clock, and auxilliary commands that specify environmental variables that control various related operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copyright Notice</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/copyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/copyright/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Clone me,&amp;rdquo; says Dolly sheepishly
 The following copyright notice applies to all files collectively called the Network Time Protocol Version 4 Distribution. Unless specifically declared otherwise in an individual file, this notice applies as if the text was explicitly included in the file.
************************************************************************ ** Copyright (c) David L. Mills 1992-2001 ** ** Permission to use, copy, modify, and distribute this software and ** its documentation for any purpose and without fee is hereby ** granted, provided that the above copyright notice appears in all ** copies and that both the copyright notice and this permission ** notice appear in supporting documentation, and that the name ** University of Delaware not be used in advertising or publicity ** pertaining to distribution of the software without specific, ** written prior permission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging Hints for Reference Clock Drivers</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/rdebug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/rdebug/</guid>
      <description>from The Wizard of Oz, L. Frank Baum
Call the girls and they&amp;rsquo;ll sweep your bugs.
 The ntpq and ntpdc utility programs can be used to debug reference clocks, either on the server itself or from another machine elsewhere in the network. The server is compiled, installed and started using the configuration file described in the ntpd page and its dependencies. If the clock appears in the ntpq utility and pe command, no errors have occurred and the daemon has started, opened the devices specified and waiting for peers and radios to come up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Executive Summary - Computer Network Time Synchronization</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/exec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/exec/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
The executive is the one on the left.
 Table of Contents  Introduction Protocol Design Issues Security Issues Computer Clock Modelling and Error Analysis Correctness Principles Data Grooming Algorithms Further Reading   Introduction The standard timescale used by most nations of the world is Coordinated UniversalTime (UTC), which is based on the Earth&amp;rsquo;s rotation about its axis, and the Gregorian Calendar, which is based on the Earth&amp;rsquo;s rotation about the Sun.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>External Clock Discipline and the Local Clock Driver</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/extern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/extern/</guid>
      <description>The NTPv4 implementation includes provisions for an external clock, where the system clock is implemented by some external hardware device. One implementation might take the form of a bus peripheral with a high resolution counter disciplined by a GPS receiver, for example. Another implementation might involve another synchronization protocol, such as the Digital Time Synchronization Service (DTSS), where the system time is disciplined to this protocol and NTP clients of the server obtain synchronization indirectly via the server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gadget Box PPS Level Converter and CHU Modem</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/gadget/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/gadget/</guid>
      <description>A Gadget Box built by Chuck Hanavin
 Table of Contents  Introduction Circuit Description Files   Introduction Many radio clocks used as a primary reference source for NTP servers produce a pulse-per-second (PPS) signal that can be used to improve accuracy to a high degree. However, the signals produced are usually incompatible with the modem interface signals on the serial ports used to connect the signal to the host.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hints and Kinks</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/hints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/hints/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
Mother in law has all the answers.
 This is an index for a set of troubleshooting notes contained in individual text files in the ./hints directory. They were supplied by various volunteers in the form of mail messages, patches or just plain word of mouth. Each note applies to a specific computer and operating system and gives information found useful in setting up the NTP distribution or site configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build new PARSE clocks</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/parsenew/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/parsenew/</guid>
      <description>Here is an attempt to sketch out what you need to do in order to add another clock to the parse driver: Currently the implementation is being cleaned up - so not all information in here is completely correct. Refer to the included code where in doubt.
 Prerequisites:
 Does the system you want the clock connect to have the include files termio.h or termios.h ? (You need that for the parse driver)  What to do:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write a Reference Clock Driver</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/howto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/howto/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
You need a little magic.
 Table of Contents  Description Conventions, Fudge Factors and Flags Files Which Need to be Changed Interface Routine Overview   Description Reference clock support maintains the fiction that the clock is actually an ordinary peer in the NTP tradition, but operating at a synthetic stratum of zero. The entire suite of algorithms used to filter the received data, select the best clocks or peers and combine them to produce a local clock correction operate just like ordinary NTP peers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kernel Model for Precision Timekeeping</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/kern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/kern/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
Exploding kernel
 The technical report 2, which is a major revision and update of an earlier report 3, describes an engineering model for a precision time-of-day function for a generic operating system. The model is based on the principles of disciplined oscillators using phase-lock loops (PLL) and frequency-lock loops (FLL) often found in the engineering literature. The model uses a hybrid PLL/FLL discipline algorithm implemented in the kernel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kernel Programming Interface for Precision Time Signals</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/kernpps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/kernpps/</guid>
      <description>The technical report 1 describes a proposed application programming interface (API) for external precision time signals, such as the pulse-per-second (PPS) signal generated by some radio clocks and cesium oscillators. The report argues for a generic capability in the ubiquitous Unix kernel, which could be used for a wide variety of measurement applications, including network time synchronization and experiments involving performance measurement and evaluation of computer networks and transmission systems. The hardware to do this requires only a serial port and a modem control lead, such as the data carrier detect (DCD) lead, which can be driven by an external source via a level converter/pulse generator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Line Disciplines and Streams Modules</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/ldisc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/ldisc/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Description PPSAPI Application Program Interface tty_clk Line Discipline/Streams Module TIOCDCDTIMESTAMP ioctl in FreeBSD ppsclock Streams Module TIOCSPPS and TIOCGETPPSEV ioctls in Solaris tty_chu Line Discipline/Streams Module (deprecated)   Description Most radio and modem clocks used for a primary (stratum-1) NTP server utilize serial ports operating at speeds of 9600 baud or greater. The intrinsic delay and jitter contributed by the serial port hardware and software driver can accumulate up to a millisecond in newer Unix systems and tens of milliseconds in older ones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miscellaneous Options</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/miscopt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/miscopt/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
We have three, now looking for more.
  broadcastdelay seconds  The broadcast and multicast modes require a special calibration to determine the network delay between the local and remote servers. Ordinarily, this is done automatically by the initial protocol exchanges between the client and server. In some cases, the calibration procedure may fail due to network or server access controls, for example. This command specifies the default delay to be used under these circumstances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitigation Rules and the prefer Keyword</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/prefer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/prefer/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
Listen carefully to what I say; it is very complicated.
 Table of Contents  Introduction The prefer Peer Peer Classification Mitigation Rules Using the Pulse-per-Second (PPS) Signal   Introduction The mechanics of the NTP algorithms which select the best data sample from each available server and the best subset of the server population have been finely crafted to resist network jitter, faults in the network or server operations, and to deliver the best possible accuracy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Options</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/monopt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/monopt/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly 
The pig watches the logs.
 Table of Contents  Monitoring Support Monitoring Commands   Monitoring Support ntpd includes a comprehensive monitoring facility suitable for continuous, long term recording of server and client timekeeping performance. See the statistics command below for a listing and example of each type of statistics currently supported. Statistic files are managed using file generation sets and scripts in the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Configuring NTP and Setting up a NTP Subnet</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/notes/</guid>
      <description>From NBS Special Publication 432 (out of print)
 Table of Contents  Introduction How NTP Works Configuring Your Subnet Configuring Your Server or Client Configuring NTP with NetInfo Ntp4 Versus Previous Versions Traffic Monitoring Address-and-Mask Restrictions Authentication Query Programs Run-Time Reconfiguration Name Resolution Dealing with Frequency Tolerance Violations Tuning Your Subnet Provisions for Leap Seconds and Accuracy Metrics Clock Support Overview Towards the Ultimate Tick Parting Shots   Introduction This document is a collection of notes concerning the use of ntpd and related programs, and on coping with the Network Time Protocol (NTP) in general.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NTP Debugging Techniques</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/debug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/debug/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
We make house calls and bring our own bugs.
 Table of Contents  Initial Startup Verifying Correct Operation Special Problems Debugging Checklist   Once the NTP software distribution has been compiled and installed and the configuration file constructed, the next step is to verify correct operation and fix any bugs that may result. Usually, the command line that starts the daemon is included in the system startup file, so it is executed only at system boot time; however, the daemon can be stopped and restarted from root at any time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NTP PARSE clock data formats</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/parsedata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/parsedata/</guid>
      <description>The parse driver currently supports several clocks with different query mechanisms. In order for you to find a sample that might be similar to a clock you might want to integrate into parse I&amp;rsquo;ll sum up the major features of the clocks (this information is distributed in the parse/clk_*.c and ntpd/refclock_parse.c files).
 Table of Contents  Meinberg clocks Raw DCF77 Data via serial line DCF77 raw time code Schmid clock Trimble SV6 ASCII time code (TAIP) ELV DCF7000 HOPF 6021 und Kompatible Diem Computime Clock WHARTON 400A Series Clock with a 404.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NTP Timescale and Leap Seconds</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/leap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/leap/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
The Mad Hatter and the March Hare are discussing whether the Teapot serial number should have two or four digits.
 Table of Contents  Introduction The NTP Timescale Conversion to Other Timescales Timescale Resolution and the Tick Interval Leap Seconds Reckoning with NTP and UTC Leap seconds   Introduction In the year 2001 the Network Time Protocol (NTP) has been in use for over two decades and remains the longest running, continuously operating application protocol in the Internet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NTP Version 4 Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/release/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
The rabbit toots to make sure you read this.
This document was last updated 4 May 2001
 Table of Contents  NTP Version 4 Release Notes Nasty Surprises Caveats   NTP Version 4 Release Notes This release of the NTP Version 4 (NTPv4) daemon for Unix, VMS and Windows (NT4 and 2000) incorporates new features and refinements to the NTP Version 3 (NTPv3) algorithms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntp-genkeys - generate public and private keys</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/genkeys/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/genkeys/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
Alice holds the key.
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Symmetric Key File Format Files Bugs   Synopsis ntp-genkeys
 Description This program generates random keys used by either or both the NTPv3/NTPv4 symmetric key or the NTPv4 public key (Autokey) cryptographic authentication schemes. By default the program generates the ntp.keys file containing 16 random symmetric keys. In addition, if the rsaref20 package is configured for the software build, the program generates cryptographic values used by the Autokey scheme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntpd - Network Time Protocol (NTP) daemon</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/ntpd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/ntpd/</guid>
      <description>from The Wizard of Oz, L. Frank Baum
The mushroom knows all the command line options.
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description How NTP Operates Frequency Discipline Operating Modes Poll Interval Control The huff-n&#39;-puff Filter Notes Command Line Options The Configuration File Files Bugs   Synopsis ntpd [ -aAbdgLmNPqx ] [ -c conffile ] [ -f driftfile ] [ -g ] [ -k keyfile ] [ -l logfile ] [ -N high ] [ -p pidfile ] [ -r broadcastdelay ] [ -s statsdir ] [ -t key ] [ -v variable ] [ -V variable ] [ -x ]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntpdate - set the date and time via NTP</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/ntpdate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/ntpdate/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
I told you it was eyeball and wristwatch.
  Disclaimer: The functionality of this program is now available in the ntpd program. See the -q command line option in the ntpd - Network Time Protocol (NTP) daemon page. After a suitable period of mourning, the ntpdate program will be retired from this distribution.
  Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Command Line Options Files Bugs   Synopsis ntpdate [ -bBdoqsuv ] [ -a key ] [ -e authdelay ] [ -k keyfile ] [ -o version ] [ -p samples ] [ -t timeout ] server [ &amp;hellip; ]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntpdc - special NTP query program</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/ntpdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/ntpdc/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
This program is a big puppy.
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Command Line Options Interactive Commands Control Message Commands Runtime Configuration Requests Bugs   Synopsis ntpdc [ -ilnps ] [ -c command ] [ host ] [ &amp;hellip; ]
 Description ntpdc is used to query the ntpd daemon about its current state and to request changes in that state. The program may be run either in interactive mode or controlled using command line arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntpq - standard NTP query program</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/ntpq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/ntpq/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
A typical NTP monitoring packet
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Internal Commands Control Message Commands Bugs   Synopsis ntpq [-inp] [-c command] [host] [&amp;hellip;]
 Description The ntpq utility program is used to query NTP servers which implement the recommended NTP mode 6 control message format about current state and to request changes in that state. The program may be run either in interactive mode or controlled using command line arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntptime - read and set kernel time variables</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/ntptime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/ntptime/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
The turtle has been swimming in the kernel.
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Options   Synopsis ntptime [ -chr ] [ -e est_error ] [ -f frequency ] [ -m max_error ] [ -o offset ] [ -s status ] [ -t time_constant]
 Description This program is useful only with special kernels described in the A Kernel Model for Precision Timekeeping page. It reads and displays time-related kernel variables using the ntp_gettime() system call.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntptrace - trace a chain of NTP servers back to the primary source</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/ntptrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/ntptrace/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
The rabbit knows the way back.
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Options Bugs   Synopsis ntptrace [ -vdn ] [ -r retries ] [ -t timeout ] [ server ]
 Description ntptrace determines where a given Network Time Protocol (NTP) server gets its time from, and follows the chain of NTP servers back to their master time source. If given no arguments, it starts with localhost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patching Procedures</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/patches/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/patches/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
The Mad Hatter needs patches.
 A distribution so widely used as this one eventually develops numerous barnacles as the result of porting to new systems, idiosyncratic new features and just plain bugs. In order to help keep order and make maintenance bearable, we ask that proposed changes to the distribution be submitted in the following form.
  Please submit patches to bugs@mail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Porting Hints</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/porting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/porting/</guid>
      <description>from The Wizard of Oz, L. Frank Baum
Porting Dorothy in Oz
 NOTEThe following procedures have been replaced by GNU automake and autoconfigure. This page is to be updated in the next release.Porting to a new machine or operating system ordinarily requires updating the ./machines directory and the ./compilers directories in order to define the build environment and autoconfigure means. You will probably have to modify the ntp_machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protocol Conformance Statement</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/biblio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/biblio/</guid>
      <description>From The Wizard of Oz, L. Frank Baum
Say it three times and it must be right.
 The Network Time Protocol (NTP) is used to synchronize the time of a computer client or server to another server or reference time source, such as a radio or satellite receiver or modem. It provides accuracies typically within a millisecond on LANs up to a few tens of milliseconds on WANs relative to Coordinated Universal Time (UTC), as provided by a Global Positioning Service (GPS) receiver, for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulse-Per-Second (PPS) Signal Interfacing</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/pps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/pps/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
Alice is trying to find the PPS signal connector.
 Some radio clocks and related timekeeping gear have a pulse-per-second (PPS) signal that can be used to discipline the local clock oscillator to a high degree of precision, typically to the order less than 10 ms in time and 0.01 parts-per-million (PPM) in frequency. The PPS signal can be connected in either of two ways: via the data carrier detector (DCD) pin of a serial port or via the acknowledge (ACK) pin of a parallel port, depending on the hardware and operating system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Start</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/quick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/quick/</guid>
      <description>FAX test image for SATNET (1979).
The baby panda was scanned at University College London and used as a FAX test image for a demonstration of the DARPA Atlantic SATNET Program and the first transatlantic Internet connection in 1978. The computing system used for that demonstration was called the Fuzzball. As it happened, this was also the first Internet multimedia presentation and the first to use a predecessor of NTP in regular operation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference Clock Audio Drivers</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/audio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/audio/</guid>
      <description>Make a little noise here.
 Table of Contents  Sound Card Drivers Shortwave Radio Drivers Debugging Aids   Sound Card Drivers There are some applications in which the computer time can be disciplined to an audio signal, rather than a serial timecode and communications port or special purpose bus peripheral. This is useful in such cases where the audio signal is sent over a telephone circuit, for example, or received directly from a shortwave receiver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference Clock Drivers</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/refclock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/refclock/</guid>
      <description>Master Time Facility at the UDel Internet Research Laboratory
 Table of Contents  Reference Clock Drivers Driver Calibration Performance Enhancements Comprehensive List of Clock Drivers   Reference Clock Drivers Support for most of the commonly available radio and modem reference clocks is included in the default configuration of the NTP daemon for Unix ntpd. Individual clocks can be activated by configuration file commands, specifically the server and fudge commands described in the ntpd program manual page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference Clock Options</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/clockopt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/clockopt/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
See the radios, all in a row.
 Table of Contents  Reference Clock Support Reference Clock Commands   Reference Clock Support The NTP Version 4 daemon supports some three dozen different radio, satellite and modem reference clocks plus a special pseudo-clock used for backup or when no other clock source is available. Detailed descriptions of individual device drivers and options can be found in the Reference Clock Drivers page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stations, Frequencies and Geographic Coordinates</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/qth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/qth/</guid>
      <description>The following data were obtained from the International Frequency List published by the ITU and other sources.
   Station Frequencies Coordinates     WWV Ft. Collins, CO 2.5/5/10/15/20 MHz 40:40:49.0N 105:02:27.0W   WWVB Ft. Collins, CO 60 kHz 40:40:28.3N 105:02:39.5W   WWVH Kauai, HI 2.5/5/10/15 MHz 21:59:26.0N 159:46:00.0W   CHU Ottawa, CA 3330/7335/14670 kHz 45:18N 75:45N   DCF77 Mainflingen, DE 77.5 kHz 50:01N 9:00E   MSF Rugby, UK 60 kHz 52:22N 1:11W   TDF Allouis, FR 162 kHz 47:10N 2:12E   JJY ( Fukushima, JAPAN ) 40 KHz 37:22 N 140:51 E   JJY ( Saga, JAPAN ) 60 KHz 33:28 N 130:11 E    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tickadj - set time-related kernel variables</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/tickadj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/tickadj/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Command Line Options Files Bugs   Synopsis tickadj [ -Aqs ] [ -a tickadj ] [ -t tick ]
 Description The tickadj program reads, and optionally modifies, several timekeeping-related variables in the running kernel in some machines, via /dev/kmem. The particular variables it is concerned with are tick, which is the number of microseconds added to the system time for a clock interrupt, tickadj, which sets the slew rate and resolution used by the adjtime system call, and dosynctodr, which indicates to the kernels on some machines whether they should internally adjust the system clock to keep it in line with time-of-day clock or not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time and Time Interval Measurement with Application to Computer and Network Performance Evaluation</title>
      <link>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/measure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://test.doc.ntp.org/archives/4.1.1/measure/</guid>
      <description>The technical memorandum: Time and Time Interval Measurement with Application to Computer and Network Performance Evaluation (PDF) describes a number of techniques for conducting experiments typical of computer network and transmission systems engineering.
In most experiments in which time is involved, it is necessary to develop estimates of time, frequency and measurement errors from a series of time measurements between the clocks of a number of computers and ancillary devices interconnected by some kind of computer network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
