<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Reference Library on NTP: Network Time Protocol</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/</link><description>Recent content in Reference Library on NTP: Network Time Protocol</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About the Pictures</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/pictures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/pictures/</guid><description>The Okefenokee Orchestra, Walt Kelly
Table of Contents Our Anthem The Pogo Collection The Alice Books The Oz Books The Maya Glyphs Photography References Our Anthem Sung to the tune of Deck the halls with boughs of holly.
Deck us all with Boston Charlie, Walla Walla, Wash., an' Kalamazoo! Nora&amp;rsquo;s freezin' on the trolley, swaller dollar cauliflower alleygaroo! Don&amp;rsquo;t we know archaic barrel, Lullaby Lilla Boy, Louisville Lou.</description></item><item><title>Analysis and Simulation of the NTP On-Wire Protocols</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/onwire/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/onwire/</guid><description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
If it walks like a duck&amp;hellip;
Last update: 12-May-2012
Table of Contents Abstract Introduction Preliminaries Basic Symmetric Mode Interleaved Symmetric Mode Interleaved Broadcast Mode Error Detection and Recovery Measured Performance Appendix A. NTP Protocol State Machines Appendix B. The NTP Simulator Program xlev.c Command Line Options Abstract This document presents a detailed analysis of the NTP on-wire protocols, including basic and interleaved, symmetric and broadcast modes.</description></item><item><title>Anatomy of a Hollerith Card</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/gallery/gallery9/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/gallery/gallery9/</guid><description>A Hollerith Card
In 1896 Herman Hollerith organized the Tabulating Machines Company, which grew in subsequent mergers to become the IBM of today. The Hollerith punched card was the principal means for recording, accounting and archiving functions, not to mention the US census, until recently. In the early 1960&amp;rsquo;s Hollerith cards were the only practical means to input programs for a IBM mainframe, but today these cards are seldom seen.</description></item><item><title>Autokey Identity Schemes</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/ident/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/ident/</guid><description>Maya glyph alautun
Table of Contents Briefing Slides Related Pages Introduction Private Certificate (PC) Cryptosystem Schnorr (IFF) Cryptosystem Guillou-Quisquater (GQ) Cryptosystem Mu-Varadharajan (MV) Cryptosystem Selected Publications Briefing Slides NTP Security Model PDF NTP Security Algorithms PDF NTP Security Protocol PDF Related Pages Autonomous Configuration Autonomous Authentication Autokey Protocol Autokey Identity Schemes Introduction While the identity scheme described in RFC 2875 is based on a ubiquitous Diffie-Hellman infrastructure, it is expensive to generate and use when compared to others described here.</description></item><item><title>Autokey Protocol</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/proto/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/proto/</guid><description>Maya glyph alautun
Table of Contents Briefing Slides Related Pages Introduction Certificate Trails Secure Groups Identity Schemes Selected Publications Briefing Slides NTP Security Model (PDF) NTP Security Algorithms (PDF) NTP Security Protocol (PDF) Related Pages Autonomous Configuration Autonomous Authentication Autokey Identity Schemes Introduction The Autokey protocol is based on the public key infrastructure (PKI) algorithms of the OpenSSL library, which includes an assortment of message digest, digital signature and encryption schemes.</description></item><item><title>Autonomous Authentication</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/autokey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/autokey/</guid><description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
Table of Contents Briefing Slides Related Pages Importance of the Problem Brief Description of Work and Results Leapseconds Table Present Status Future Plans Selected Publications Briefing Slides NTP Security Model PDF NTP Security Algorithms PDF NTP Security Protocol PDF Related Pages Autonomous Configuration Autokey Protocol Autokey Identity Schemes Importance of the Problem The missions considered in this project include autonomous networks that might be deployed from a reconnaissance vehicle over a battlefield or from a space probe over a planetary surface.</description></item><item><title>Autonomous Configuration</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/autocfg/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/autocfg/</guid><description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
Table of Contents Importance of the Problem Brief Description of Work and Results NTP Multicast/Manycast Support Present Status and Future Plans Further Information Selected Publications Importance of the Problem The missions considered in this project involve autonomous sensors that might be deployed from a helicopter over a battlefield or from a space probe over a planetary surface. Once deployed, the sensor network must operate autonomously using an ad-hoc wireless infrastructure as sensors are deployed or destroyed or the network is damaged or compromised and then repaired.</description></item><item><title>Autonomous Networks</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/autonet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/autonet/</guid><description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
Table of Contents Importance of the Problem Approach Further Information Importance of the Problem The Network Time Protocol (NTP) is widely used in the Internet to synchronize computer clocks. It is supported by well over a hundred primary time servers located in many countries, together with a hierarchical, distributed subnetwork of well over 100,000 servers and clients scattered all over the globe.</description></item><item><title>Backroom Test Facility</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/backroom/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/backroom/</guid><description>pogo, Walt Kelly
In case of fan failure
Table of Contents The Backroom Network Facilities References The Backroom The Backroom Test Facility (BTF) is located at 43 The Horseshoe, Newark, DE 19711, geographic coordinates 39:42:02.915N, 75:46:52.046W. The BTF presently includes five Unix workstations, three Windows/XP PCs, a Windows/XP laptop, color laser printer, high resolution scanner and assorted hubs and routers connected together with 100-Mb Ethernet fiber segments and a 54-Mb WiFi backup.</description></item><item><title>Bibliography on Computer Network Time Synchronization</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/biblio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/biblio/</guid><description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
It isn&amp;rsquo;t clear whether the mushroom is a controlled substance or a food item.
Table of Contents Contributors Bibliography The following citations have at least some relevance to the field of computer network time synchronization. Where multiple citations to the same work occur, only the latest should be used; earlier ones are included only for record. Those documents available online are indicated following the citation.</description></item><item><title>CAIRN/DARTnet Collaboration</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/dartnet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/dartnet/</guid><description>Researchers involved: David Mills, Jon Crowcroft (UCL), Kenneth Carlberg (SAIC)
Funding: Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency
Status: This project was completed in 2001. This page is for historic record.
Table of Contents Briefing Slides Importance of the Problem Brief Description of Work and Results Future Plans Briefing Slides CAIRN/DARTnet Collaboration PDF DCnet Research Network PDF Importance of the Problem Provision of good real-time, multicast services using a best-effort infrastructure like the Internet is generally considered difficult at best.</description></item><item><title>Collaboration Resources</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/resource/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/resource/</guid><description>FAX test image for SATNET (1979).
The baby panda was scanned at University College London and used as a FAX test image for a demonstration of the DARPA Atlantic SATNET Program and the first transatlantic Internet connection in 1979. The computing system used for that demonstration was called the Fuzzball. As it happened, this was also the first Internet multimedia presentation and the first to use NTP in regular operation. The image was widely copied and used for testing throughout much of the 1980s.</description></item><item><title>Covered Bridge Farms</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/gallery/gallery1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/gallery/gallery1/</guid><description>Covered Bridge Farms is on older development about 2.4 km west of campus. It is nestled in a corner of the state next to Maryland and Pennsylvania where the state boundaries come together.
43 The Horseshoe Our house is surrounded by a grove of self-pruning trees, some of which make good antenna towers.
How To Get Here
43 The Horseshoe
43 The Mailbox
Front Yard
Driveway
Light Patterns
Back Porch</description></item><item><title>Data Concentrator Project</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/gallery/gallery7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/gallery/gallery7/</guid><description>I was chief nerd for several projects in the fifteen years I was with U Michigan, first in electrical engineering and then in computer science. This is one of them.
In the late 60s IBM was the crushing giant, while Digital Equipment Corporation (DEC) was yet a pipsqueak. The U Michigan Computing Center had a giant - a two-processor System 360 Model 67 processor with a dazzling one megabyte of core memory.</description></item><item><title>DCnet Research Network</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/dcnet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/dcnet/</guid><description>Table of Contents Briefing Slides Network Infrastructure Precision Timekeeping and Timecasting Briefing Slides CAIRN/DARTnet Collaboration PDF DCnet Research Network PDF Network Infrastructure We use our DCnet laboratory network (128.4 subnets 1-9) for protocol development, experiments and performance evaluation, as well as day-to-day videoconferencing with our collaborators throughout the US and western Europe. About two dozen workstations and PCs provide over 9.6 GB of RAM and 1900 GB of disk resources.</description></item><item><title>Evans Hall</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/gallery/gallery3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/gallery/gallery3/</guid><description>Evans Hall is home for the Electrical and Computer Engineering Department. Some folks are located in next-door DuPont Hall along with the cleanroom facilities.
Evans Hall
Evans Hall
102 is just right of the door.
Evans Hall
Classy large windows catch the rays.
Evans Hall (left) and DuPont Hall
Amateur Radio Club W3UD uses the hut and tower on the roof.
W3UD Newly Renovated Ham Shack
Machine Room Front-End Power</description></item><item><title>Executive Summary: Computer Network Time Synchronization</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/exec/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/exec/</guid><description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
The executive is the one on the left.
Last update: 12-May-2012
Table of Contents Abstract Introduction Protocol Design Issues Precision and Accuracy Security Issues Computer Clock Modeling and Error Analysis Correctness Principles Data Grooming Algorithms Clock Discipline Algorithm Further Reading Abstract The Network Time Protocol (NTP) and other protocols are used to synchronize the clocks in an estimated total of 25 million servers, workstations and PCs of the public Internet and private networks.</description></item><item><title>IEEE 1588 Precision Time Protocol (PTP)</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/ptp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/ptp/</guid><description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
Public transport in Oz
Last update 18-May-2012
Table of Contents Abstract Introduction Timestamp Capture On-Wire Protocols Master-Slave Mode Broadcast Mode Routers and Switches Conclusions References Abstract This document explores the similarities and differences between the Network Time Protocol (NTP) and the IEEE 1588 Precision Time Protocol (PTP). For the configurations considered in this document, these protocols provide clock synchronization in high-speed local area networks.</description></item><item><title>Internet Research Laboratory</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/lab/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/lab/</guid><description>The Okefenokee Swamp, Walt Kelly
Pogo Possum, our mascot, was created by Walt Kelly, who invented a delicious menagerie of swamp creatures. All of the machines on our DCnet research network 128.4 are named after these creatures. The initials DC stand for District of Columbia, Distributed Computing, Drastically Corrupted or Direct Current, depending on the mood of the audience and voltage of the speaker.
Table of Contents Briefing Slides General Description Briefing Slides CAIRN/DARTnet Collaboration PDF DCnet Research Network PDF General Description The Internetworking Research Laboratory (IRL) is in 121 Evans Hall, geographic coordinates 39:40:48.</description></item><item><title>Michigan Terminal System</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/gallery/gallery8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/gallery/gallery8/</guid><description>During much of the 1960s I was a staff member at the U Michigan Computing Center. I worked with a bunch of other guys on various hardward and software projects, one of which is described on this page.
The Michigan Terminal System (MTS), along with Multics at MIT, were the first operational virtual memory operating systems in the world. The pictures here, taken circa 1969, give some idea of the computing systems of that era.</description></item><item><title>Network Time Synchronization Research Project</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/ntp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/ntp/</guid><description>Maya glyph alautun
Researchers involved: David Mills, graduate students and many volunteers
Funding: Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA), National Science Foundation (NSF), Navy Surface Weapons Center (NSWC) and Jet Propulsion Laboratory/NASA
Last update: 13-May-2012
Table of Contents Briefing Slides Importance of the Problem Brief Description of Work and Results Future Plans Selected Publications Briefing Slides Network Time Protocol (NTP) General Overview PDF NTP Architecture, Protocol and Algorithms PDF NTP Procedure Descriptions and Flow Diagrams PDF NTP Clock Discipline Principles PDF NTP Security Model PDF NTP Security Algorithms PDF NTP Security Protocol PDF NTP Precision Synchronization PDF NTP Performance Analysis PDF NTP Algorithm Analysis PDF NTP Interleaved Protocol for LANs and Space Data Links PowerPoint | PDF Long-Range Dependency Effects in NTP Timekeeping PDF Importance of the Problem The Network Time Protocol (NTP) is widely used in the Internet to synchronize computer clocks to national standard time.</description></item><item><title>Network Time Synchronization: the Network Time Protocol on Earth and in Space, Second Edition</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/book/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/book/</guid><description>Mills, David L. Computer Network Time Synchronization: the Network Time Protocol on Earth and in Space, Second Edition, CRC Press 2011, 466 pp.
ISBN 978-1-4398-1463-5
Author David L. Mills, PhD Electrical and Computer Engineering Department and Computer and Information Systems Department University of Delaware, Newark, DE 19716 mills@udel.edu https://www.eecis.udel.edu/~mills/ Dr. David L. Mills is Professo Emeritus of Electrical and Computer Engineering and Computer and Information Sciences at the University of Delaware.</description></item><item><title>NTP Discrete Event Simulator</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/ntpsim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/ntpsim/</guid><description>from pogo, Walt Kelly
Researchers involved: David Mills, graduate student Harish Nair
Funding: Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency (DARPA) and Jet Propulsion Laboratory/NASA
Table of Contents Briefing Slides Importance of the Problem Brief Description of Work and Results Future Work Briefing Slides NTP Architecture, Protocol And Algorithms PDF NTP Clock Discipline algorithm PDF Importance of the Problem Evaluating NTP performance has always been a time consuming process, as the measurement periods can be long - in the order of days in some cases - and the data collected must be processed and converted to a useful form.</description></item><item><title>NTP Security Analysis</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/security/</guid><description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
The Cheshire Cat is our resident cryptographer.
Last update 14 May 2012
Table of Contents Abstract 1. Introduction 1.1 Threats and Countermeasures 1.2 Protocol Layers 2. On-Wire Protocol Layer 3. Message Digest Layer 4. Autokey Sequence Layer 4.1. Client/Server Mode 4.2. Symmetric Modes 4.3 Broadcast Modes 5. Autokey Protocol Layer 5.1. Client/Server and Symmetric Modes 5.2. Broadcast Modes 6. Conclusions 7. Parting Shots 7.</description></item><item><title>NTP Timestamp Calculations</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/time/</guid><description>from The Wizard of Oz, L. Frank Baum
Public transport in Oz
Last update 26-May-2012
Table of Contents Abstract 1. Introduction 2. Data Formats 3. Datestamps and Timestamps as Finite Groups 4. Time Difference Calculations 5. On-Wire Protocol Implications Abstract This document presents a mathematical analysis of the principles of clock offset and roundtrip delay calculations used by the Network Time Protocol (NTP). The analysis is based on the properties of finite additive groups using two&amp;rsquo;s complement arithmetic.</description></item><item><title>Personal Stuff</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/david/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/david/</guid><description>43 The Horseshoe, Newark, DE 19711
Phone: (302) 737-9212
Mills family pages
My hobbies include hiking, amateur radio and photography, although I haven&amp;rsquo;t had much time for the latter two in recent years. For recreational reading, I enjoy the study of ancient civilizations; in particular, their writing and calendar systems. I have followed with great interest the recent progress in deciphering the written language of the Classic Maya, which consists of artistic glyphs.</description></item><item><title>The Classic Maya Calendar and Day Numbering System</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/maya/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/maya/</guid><description>one of the Maya day-glyphs for Kin
Table of Contents Introduction The Maya Calendar The Calendar Round and Long Count Dates Reckoning the Maya and Gregorian Calendars References Introduction The calendar systems used in the ancient world reflect the agricultural, political and ritual needs characteristic of the societies in which they flourished. Astronomical observations to establish the winter and summer solstices were in use three to four millennia ago 1.</description></item><item><title>The Fuzzball</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/gallery/gallery10/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/gallery/gallery10/</guid><description>The last known Fuzzball (1990)
The Fuzzball The Fuzzball is an operating system and a package of applications for the Digital Equipment Corporation (DEC) PDP11 family of computers, including the LSI-11 board-level components. The package was conceived in 1971 as a replacement for the RAMP operating system for the DEC PDP8 3. It later was evolved as a virtual machine supporting the DEC RT-11 operating system and early developmental versions of the TCP/IP protocol and applications suite.</description></item><item><title>The Mills Pages</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/fam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/fam/</guid><description>In the baby photo at left (circa 1971), that&amp;rsquo;s me (b 1938), Beverly (b 1942), Eileen (b 1965), and Keith (b 1968).
Bev is a classically trained singer (lyric soprano) and musician (violin, piano) and is a retired music teacher in Wilmington, DE. She has a BA in Music and a Second Degree Brown Belt in Judo. Eileen works as a computer network technician in Newark, DE. She has a MCSE and volunteers at Tri State Bird Rescue, one of only three in the country.</description></item><item><title>The NTP Era and Era Numbering</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/y2k/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/y2k/</guid><description>from The Wizard of Oz, L. Frank Baum
Era dynamically aloft
Last update 12-May-2012
Table of Contents Abstract 1. Introduction 2. The UTC Timescale 3. The NTP Timescale 4. The NTP Era Abstract The Network Time Protocol (NTP) specification defines the timescale in terms of timestamps and datestamps. Timestamps define an era spanning 136 years, while datestamps extend over multiple eras spanning the age of the Universe to when the stars grow dim.</description></item><item><title>The NTP Timescale and Leap Seconds</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/leap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/leap/</guid><description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
The Mad Hatter and the March Hare are discussing whether the Teapot serial number should have two or four digits.
Last update: 12-May-2012
Table of Contents Abstract Introduction How UTC Reckons with Leap Seconds How NTP and POSIX Reckon with Leap Seconds How NTP and POSIX Number the Seconds How NTP Implements Leap Seconds Parting Shots Appendix A. Specimen NIST leap-seconds.list File Abstract The timescale used by the Network Time Protocol (NTP) is based on coordinated univeral time (UTC), which itself is based on the Earth rotation about its axis.</description></item><item><title>Time and Frequency Standard Station Information</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/qth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/qth/</guid><description>From NBS Special Publication 432 (1979 edition, now out of print)
NBS Special Publication 432 (current edition)
The following data were obtained from the International Frequency List published by the ITU and other sources.
Station Frequencies Coordinates WWV Ft. Collins, CO 2.5/5/10/15/20 MHz 40째 40' 49.0&amp;quot; N, 105째 2' 27.0&amp;quot; W WWVB Ft. Collins, CO 60 kHz 40째 40' 28.3&amp;quot; N, 105째 2' 39.</description></item><item><title>Time and Standard Frequency Station TDF (France)</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/tdf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/tdf/</guid><description>Information provided by Richard B. Langley, University of New Brunswick
Station: TDF, Allouis, France
Address: Centre National d'Etudes des Telecommunications
PAB - STC - Etalons de frequence et de temps
196 avenue Henri Ravera
F - 92220 Bagneux
France
Coordinates: 47d 10' N, 2d 12' E
Frequency: 162 kHz
Power: 2,000 kW
Schedule: continuous except every Tuesday from 01:00 to 05:00 UTC
Form of Time Signals:
TDF is an amplitude modulated longwave broadcasting station,
transmitting the programs of the France-Inter Network of Telediffusion
de France (TDF).</description></item><item><title>Time Synchronization for Space Data Links</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/proximity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/proximity/</guid><description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
Turtle wins the race.
Last update: 07-Jun-2012
Table of Contents Abstract Introduction Proximity-1 Protocol Proximity-1 Time Service Proposed Proximity-1 Interleaved Time Service (PITS) PITS Protocol Operations Parting Shots Further Reading References Abstract The Consultive Committee on Space Data Systems (CCSDS) has defined the Proximity-1 Protocol for use by space data links between vehicles in the vicinity of Mars and in the vicinity of the Moon.</description></item><item><title>Timestamp Capture Principles</title><link>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/stamp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://doc.ntp.org/reflib/stamp/</guid><description>from Wizard of Oz, L. Frank Baum
Ya gotta salute the principles.
Last update 12-May-2012
David L. Mills and Stuart Venters
Table of Contents Abstract 1. Introduction 2. Application Clock Interface 2.1 Structural Metrics 2.2. Application Clock Interface Algorithm 2.3. Entropy Mask Algorithm 3. Improving the System Clock 4. Requirements and Principles of Hardware Timestamping 5. Timestamp Transposition 6. Error Analysis 7. Reciprocity Errors 8. Hardware Timestamping 9. Driver Timestamping 10.</description></item></channel></rss>