<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>4.2.8-series on NTP: Network Time Protocol</title>
    <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 4.2.8-series on NTP: Network Time Protocol</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Access Control Commands and Options</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/accopt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/accopt/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
The skunk watches for intruders and sprays.
 Commands and Options Unless noted otherwise, further information about these commands is on the Access Control Support page.
 discard [ average avg ][ minimum min ] [ monitor prob ] Set the parameters of the rate control facility which protects the server from client abuse. If the limited flag is present in the ACL, packets that violate these limits are discarded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Access Control Support</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/access/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/access/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
The skunk watches for intruders and sprays.
 The ntpd daemon implements a general purpose access control list (ACL) containing address/match entries sorted first by increasing address values and then by increasing mask values. A match occurs when the bitwise AND of the mask and the packet source address is equal to the bitwise AND of the mask and address in the list. The list is searched in order with the last match found defining the restriction flags associated with the entry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association Management</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/assoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/assoc/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
Make sure who your friends are.
 Table of Contents  Association Modes Client/Server Mode Symmetric Active/Passive Mode Broadcast/Multicast Modes Manycast and Pool Modes Poll Interval Management Burst Options   Association Modes This page describes the various modes of operation provided in NTPv4. There are three types of associations in NTP: persistent, preemptable and ephemeral. Persistent associations are mobilized by a configuration command and never demobilized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authentication Commands and Options</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/authopt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/authopt/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
Our resident cryptographer; now you see him, now you don&amp;rsquo;t.
 Commands and Options Unless noted otherwise, further information about these commands is on the Authentication Support page.
 automax [logsec] Specifies the interval between regenerations of the session key list used with the Autokey protocol, as a power of 2 in seconds. Note that the size of the key list for each association depends on this interval and the current poll interval.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authentication Support</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/authentic/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/authentic/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
Our resident cryptographer; now you see him, now you don&amp;rsquo;t.
 Table of Contents  Introduction Symmetric Key Cryptography Microsoft Windows Authentication Public Key Cryptography   Introduction This page describes the various cryptographic authentication provisions in NTPv4. Authentication support allows the NTP client to verify that servers are in fact known and trusted and not intruders intending accidentally or intentionally to masquerade as a legitimate server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autokey Public-Key Authentication</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/autokey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/autokey/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Introduction Autokey Subnets Subnet Group Names Secure Groups Configuration - Authentication Schemes Configuration - Identity Schemes Identity Schemes and Cryptotypes Files   Introduction This distribution includes support for the Autokey public key algorithms and protocol specified in RFC 5906 &amp;ldquo;Network Time Protocol Version 4: Autokey Specification&amp;rdquo;. This support is available only if the OpenSSL library has been installed and the --enable-autokey option is specified when the distribution is built.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automatic Server Discovery Schemes</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/discover/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/discover/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
Make sure who your friends are.
 Table of Contents  Introduction Association Management Broadcast/Multicast Scheme Manycast Scheme Server Pool Scheme   Introduction This page describes the automatic server discovery schemes provided in NTPv4. There are three automatic server discovery schemes: broadcast/multicast, many cast, and server pool, which are described on this page. The broadcast/multicast and many cast schemes utilize the ubiquitous broadcast or one-to-many paradigm native to IPv4 and IPv6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Installation</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/install/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/install/</guid>
      <description>These are generic *nix installation instructions.
For Windows/NT, please see the Windows NT Hints.
Table of Contents  Using Configure Compilers and Options Compiling For Multiple Architectures Installation Names Optional Features Specifying the System Type Sharing Defaults Operation Controls   Using Configure The configure shell script attempts to guess correct values for various system-dependent variables used during compilation. It uses those values to create a Makefile in each directory of the package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build Options</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/config/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/config/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
Gnu autoconfigure tools are in the backpack.
 Most modern software distributions include an autoconfigure utility which customizes the build and install configuration according to the specific hardware, operating system, and file system conventions. For NTP this utility is called configure, which is run before building and installing the program components. For most installations no additional actions are required other than running configure with no options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building and Installing the Distribution</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/build/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/build/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
For putting out compiler fires.
 Table of Contents  Building and Installing the Distribution Building and Installing for Unix Building and Installing for Windows Configuration If You Have Problems Additional make Commands   Building and Installing the Distribution It is not possible in a software distribution such as this to support every individual computer and operating system with a common executable, even with the same system but different versions and options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clock Cluster Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/cluster/</guid>
      <description>The clock cluster algorithm processes the truechimers produced by the clock select algorithm to produce a list of survivors. These survivors are used by the mitigation algorithms to discipline the system clock. The cluster algorithm operates in a series of rounds, where at each round the truechimer furthest from the offset centroid is pruned from the population. The rounds are continued until a specified termination condition is met. This page discusses the algorithm in detail.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clock Discipline Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/discipline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/discipline/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  General Overview Clock Discipline Operations Loop Dynamics Clock Initialization and Management   General Overview At the heart of the NTP specification and reference implementation is the clock discipline algorithm, which is best described as an adaptive parameter, hybrid phase/frequency-lock feedback loop. It is an intricately crafted algorithm that automatically adapts for optimum performance while minimizing network overhead. Operation is in two modes, phase-lock loop (PLL), which is used at poll intervals below the Allan intercept, by default 2048 s, and frequency-lock loop (FLL), which is used above that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clock Filter Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/filter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/filter/</guid>
      <description>The clock filter algorithm processes the offset and delay samples produced by the on-wire protocol for each peer process separately. It uses a sliding window of eight samples and picks out the sample with the least expected error. This page describes the algorithm design principles along with an example of typical performance.
Figure 1: Wedge Scattergram
Figure 1 shows a typical wedge scattergram plotting sample points of offset versus delay collected over a 24-hr period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clock Select Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/select/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/select/</guid>
      <description>The clock select algorithm determines from a set of sources , which are correct (truechimers) and which are not (falsetickers) according to a set of formal correctness assertions. The principles are based on the observation that the maximum error in determining the offset of a candidate cannot exceed one-half the roundtrip delay to the primary reference clock at the time of measurement. This must be increased by the maximum error that can accumulate since then.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clock State Machine</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/clock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/clock/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  General Overview Panic Threshold Step and Stepout Thresholds Hold Timer Operating Intervals State Transition Function   General Overview In the NTPv4 specification and reference implementation a state machine is used to manage the system clock under exceptional conditions, as when the daemon is first started or when encountering severe network congestion. This page describes the design and operation of the state machine in detail.
The state machine is activated upon receipt of an update by the clock discipline algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Command Index</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/comdex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/comdex/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carrol
The Mad Hatter says &amp;ldquo;Bring it on&amp;rdquo;.
 Related Links  Access Control Commands and Options Authentication Commands and Options Server Commands and Options Monitoring Commands and Options Reference Clock Commands and Options Miscellaneous Commands and Options  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration File Definition (Advanced)</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntp.conf-advanced/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntp.conf-advanced/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
Racoon is shooting configuration bugs.
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Files High-Level Description Detailed Description Guidelines for Adding Configuration Commands   Synopsis The NTP configuration process is driven by a phrase-structure grammar which is used to specify the format of the configuration commands and the actions needed to build an abstract syntax tree (AST). The grammar is fed to a parser generator (Bison) which produces a parser for the configuration file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Copyright Notice</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/copyright/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/copyright/</guid>
      <description>Clone me, says Dolly sheepishly.
 The following copyright notice applies to all files collectively called the Network Time Protocol Version 4 Distribution. Unless specifically declared otherwise in an individual file, this entire notice applies as if the text was explicitly included in the file.
************************************************************************ ** Copyright (c) University of Delaware 1992-2015 ** ** Permission to use, copy, modify, and distribute this software and ** its documentation for any purpose with or without fee is hereby ** granted, provided that the above copyright notice appears in all ** copies and that both the copyright notice and this permission ** notice appear in supporting documentation, and that the name ** University of Delaware not be used in advertising or publicity ** pertaining to distribution of the software without specific, ** written prior permission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging Reference Clock Drivers</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/rdebug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/rdebug/</guid>
      <description>from The Wizard of Oz, L. Frank Baum
Call the girls and they&amp;rsquo;ll sweep your bugs.
 The ntpq and ntpdc utility programs can be used to debug reference clocks, either on the server itself or from another machine elsewhere in the network. The server is compiled, installed and started using the configuration file described in the ntpd page and its dependencies. If the clock appears in the ntpq utility and pe command, no errors have occurred and the daemon has started, opened the devices specified, and is waiting for peers and radios to come up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event Messages and Status Words</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/decode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/decode/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
Caterpillar knows all the error codes, which is more than most of us do.
 Table of Contents  Introduction System Status Word Peer Status Word Clock Status Word Flash Status Word Kiss Codes Crypto Messages   Introduction This page lists the status words, event messages, and error codes used for ntpd reporting and monitoring. Status words are used to display the current status of the running program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>External Clock Discipline and the Local Clock Driver</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/extern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/extern/</guid>
      <description>The NTPv4 implementation includes provisions for an external clock, where the system clock is implemented by some external hardware device. One implementation might take the form of a bus peripheral with a high resolution counter disciplined by a GPS receiver, for example. Another implementation might involve another synchronization protocol, such as the Digital Time Synchronization Service (DTSS), where the system time is disciplined to this protocol and NTP clients of the server obtain synchronization indirectly via the server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hints and Kinks</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/hints/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/hints/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
Mother in law has all the answers.
 This is an index for a set of troubleshooting notes contained in individual text files in the ./hints directory. They were supplied by various volunteers in the form of mail messages, patches or just plain word of mouth. Each note applies to a specific computer and operating system and gives information found useful in setting up the NTP distribution or site configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historical Notes</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/history/</guid>
      <description>Historical Notes on NTP Upgrades This is an interim report on recent upgrades to the NTPv4 reference implementation code base and documentation. This report documents the upgrade program, which began in June 2007 and continued until March 2008. It is very important to recognize that this historic document describes the upgrade status as of 2008. Additional upgrades have been implemented since then. As of mid 2011, the additional upgrades are documented on the NTP Version 4 Release Notes page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How NTP Works</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/warp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/warp/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Abstract Introduction and Overview NTP Timescale and Data Formats Architecture and Algorithms   Abstract This page and its dependencies contain a technical description of the Network Time Protocol (NTP) architecture and operation. It is intended for administrators, operators and monitoring personnel. Additional information for nontechnical readers can be found in the white paper Executive Summary: Computer Network Time Synchronization. While this page and its dependencies are primarily concerned with NTP, additional information on related protocols can be found in the white papers IEEE 1588 Precision Time Protocol (PTP) and Time Synchronization for Space Data Links.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write a Reference Clock Driver</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/howto/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/howto/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
You need a little magic.
 Table of Contents  Description Conventions, Fudge Factors and Flags Files Which Need to be Changed Interface Routine Overview Pulse-per-Second Interface   Description NTP reference clock support maintains the fiction that the clock is actually an ordinary server in the NTP tradition, but operating at a synthetic stratum of zero. The entire suite of algorithms filter the received data and select the best sources to correct the system clock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kernel Model for Precision Timekeeping</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/kern/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/kern/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
Alice finds the kernel a house of cards.
 The technical report 2, which is a revision and update of an earlier report 3, describes an engineering model for a precision clock discipline function for a generic operating system. The model is the same hybrid phase/frequecy-lock feedback loop used by ntpd, but implemented in the kernel. The code described in 2 is included in Solaris and Digital/Compaq/HP Tru64.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leap Second Processing</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/leap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/leap/</guid>
      <description>About every eighteen months the International Earth Rotation Service (IERS) issues a bulletin announcing the insertion of a leap second in the Universal Coordinated Time (UTC) timescale. Ordinarily, this happens at the end of the last day of June or December; but, in principle, it could happen at the end of any month. While these bulletins are available on the Internet at IERS, advance notice of leap seconds is also available in signals broadcast from national time and frequency stations, in GPS signals and in telephone modem services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making PARSE Clocks</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/parsenew/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/parsenew/</guid>
      <description>Here is an attempt to sketch out what you need to do in order to add another clock to the parse driver: Currently the implementation is being cleaned up - so not all information in here is completely correct. Refer to the included code where in doubt.
 Prerequisite: Does the system you want the clock to connect to have the include files termio.h or termios.h? They are needed by the parse driver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miscellaneous Commands and Options</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/miscopt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/miscopt/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
We have three, now looking for more.
 Commands and Options  broadcastdelay delay  In broadcast and multicast modes, means are required to determine the network delay between the server and client. Ordinarily, this is done automatically by the initial calibration exchanges between the client and server. In some cases, the exchange might not be possible due to network or server access controls. The value of delay is by default zero, in which case the exchange is enabled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mitigation Rules and the prefer Keyword</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/prefer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/prefer/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
Listen carefully to what I say; it is very complicated.
 Table of Contents  Introduction and Overview Combine Algorithm Anti-Clockhop Algorithm Peer Classification The prefer Peer Mitigation Rules The minsane Option   Introduction and Overview This page summarizes the criteria for choosing from among the survivors of the clock cluster algorithm a set of contributors to the clock discipline algorithm. The criteria are very meticulous, since they have to handle many different scenarios that may be optimized for special circumstances, including some scenarios designed to support planetary and deep space missions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring Options</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/monopt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/monopt/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
Pig was hired to watch the logs.
 Table of Contents  Naming Conventions Monitoring Commands and Options File Set Types   Naming Conventions The ntpd includes a comprehensive monitoring facility which collects statistical data of various types and writes the data to files associated with each type at defined events or intervals. The files associated with a particular type are collectively called the generation file set for that type.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NTP Bug Reporting Procedures</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/bugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/bugs/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
The rabbit toots to make sure you read this.
 Security Bug Reporting Procedures If you find or suspect a security-related program bug in this distribution, please send a report to security@ntp.org. Please do not contact developers directly.
 Non-Security Bug Reporting Procedures If you find or suspect a non-security related program or documentation bug in this distribution, please send a report to the NTP Public Service Project Bug Tracking System (Bugzilla).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NTP Configuration File User’s Manual</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntp.conf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntp.conf/</guid>
      <description>This document describes the configuration file for the NTP Project’s ntpd program. This software is released under the NTP license.
Description The behavior of ntpd can be changed by a configuration file, by default ntp.conf.
 Notes The ntp.conf configuration file is read at initial startup by the ntpd daemon in order to specify the synchronization sources, modes and other related information. Usually, it is installed in the /etc directory, but could be installed elsewhere (see the daemon’s -c command line option).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NTP Debugging Techniques</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/debug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/debug/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
We make house calls and bring our own bugs.
 Table of Contents  Initial Startup Verifying Correct Operation Large Frequency Errors Access Controls Large Delay Variations Cryptographic Authentication Debugging Checklist   Initial Startup This page discusses ntpd program monitoring and debugging techniques using the ntpq - standard NTP query program, either on the local server or from a remote machine. In special circumstances the ntpdc - special NTP query program, can be useful, but its use is not covered here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NTP Interleaved Modes</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/xleave/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/xleave/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
You need a little magic.
 In the protocol described in the NTP specification and reference implementation up to now, the transmit timestamp, which is captured before the message digest is computed and the packet queued for output, is properly called as a softstamp. The receive timestamp, which is captured after the input driver interrupt routine and before the packet is queued for input, is properly called a drivestamp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NTP PARSE clock data formats</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/parsedata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/parsedata/</guid>
      <description>The parse driver currently supports several clocks with different query mechanisms. In order for you to find a sample that might be similar to a clock you might want to integrate into parse I&amp;rsquo;ll sum up the major features of the clocks (this information is distributed in the parse/clk_*.c and ntpd/refclock_parse.c files).
 Table of Contents  Meinberg clocks Raw DCF77 Data via serial line DCF77 raw time code Schmid clock Trimble SV6 ASCII time code (TAIP) ELV DCF7000 HOPF 6021 und Kompatible Diem Computime Clock WHARTON 400A Series Clock with a 404.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NTP Version 4 Release Notes</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/release/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/release/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
The rabbit toots to make sure you read this.
Table of Contents  New Features Changes and Upgrades Since the NTPv3 Version (xntp3-5) Nasty Surprises   NTP has been under development for almost 30 years, but the paint ain&amp;rsquo;t dry even now. This release of the NTP Version 4 (NTPv4) distribution for Unix, VMS and Windows incorporates new features and refinements, but retaining backwards compatibility with older versions, including NTPv3 and NTPv2, but not NTPv1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntp-keygen - generate public and private keys</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/keygen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/keygen/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
Alice holds the key.
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Running the program Command Line Options Random Seed File Cryptographic Data Files Bugs   Synopsis ntp-keygen [ -deGHIMPT ] [ -b modulus ] [ -c [ RSA-MD2 | RSA-MD5 | RSA-SHA | RSA-SHA1 | RSA-MDC2 | RSA-RIPEMD160 | DSA-SHA | DSA-SHA1 ] ] [ -C cipher ] [-i group ] [ -l days] [ -m modulus ] [ -p passwd1 ] [ -q passwd2 ] [ -S [ RSA | DSA ] ] [ -s host ] [ -V nkeys ]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntp-wait - waits until ntpd is in synchronized state</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntp-wait/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntp-wait/</guid>
      <description>Synopsis ntp-wait [ -v ] [ -n tries ] [ -s seconds ]
 Description The ntp-wait program blocks until ntpd is in synchronized state. This can be useful at boot time, to delay the boot sequence until after ntpd -g has set the time.
 Command Line Options  -n tries Number of tries before giving up. The default is 1000. -s seconds Seconds to sleep between tries. The default is 6 seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntpd - Network Time Protocol (NTP) daemon</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntpd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntpd/</guid>
      <description>from The Wizard of Oz, L. Frank Baum
You need help from the monkeys.
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Command Line Options The Configuration File Files   Synopsis ntpd [ -46aAbdDgLmnNqx ] [ -c conffile ] [ -f driftfile ] [ -i jaildir ] [ -I InterfaceOrAddress ] [ -k keyfile ] [ -l logfile ] [ -p pidfile ] [ -P priority ] [ -r broadcastdelay ] [ -s statsdir ] [ -t key ] [ -u user[:group] ] [ -U interface_update_interval ] [ -v variable ] [ -V variable ]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntpd System Log Messages</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/msyslog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/msyslog/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
The log can be shrill at times.
 Table of Contents  Introduction Protocol Module Clock Discipline Module Cryptographic Module   Introduction You have come here because you found a cryptic message in the system log. This page by no means lists all messages that might be found, since new ones come and old ones go. Generally, however, the most common ones will be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntpdate - set the date and time via NTP</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntpdate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntpdate/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
I told you it was eyeball and wristwatch.
  Disclaimer: This program has known bugs and deficiencies and nobody has volunteered to fix them in a long time. The good news is the functionality originally intended for this program is available in the ntpd and sntp programs. See the Deprecating ntpdate topic for a thorough discussion and analysis of the issues. See the -q command line option in ntpd - Network Time Protocol (NTP) daemon or sntp - Simple Network Time Protocol (SNTP) Client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntpdc - special NTP query program</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntpdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntpdc/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
This program is a big, deprecated puppy.
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Command Line Options Interactive Commands Control Message Commands Runtime Configuration Requests Bugs   Synopsis ntpdc [ -46dilnps ] [ -c command ] [ host ] [ &amp;hellip; ]
 Description  ntpdc is deprecated - please use ntpq now, as it uses a more sane interface and can provide all of the information that ntpdc used to provide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntpdsim - Network Time Protocol (NTP) Simulator</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntpdsim_new/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntpdsim_new/</guid>
      <description>from The Wizard of Oz, L. Frank Baum
All in a row.
 Table of Contents  Description Configuration Sample Configuration File   Description The ntpdsim program is used to simulate and study the behavior of an NTP daemon that derives its time from a number of different simulated time sources (servers). Each simulated server can be configured to have a different time offset, frequency offset, propagation delay, processing delay, network jitter and oscillator wander.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntpdsim - Network Time Protocol (NTP) simulator</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntpdsim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntpdsim/</guid>
      <description>from The Wizard of Oz, L. Frank Baum
All in a row.
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Command Line Options Files   Synopsis ntpdsim [ -B bdly ] [ -C snse ] [ -O clk_time ] [ -S sim_time ] [ -T ferr ] [ -W fsne ] [ -Y ndly ] [ -X pdly ]
 Description The ntpdsim program is an adaptation of the ntpd operating system daemon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntpq - standard NTP query program</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntpq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntpq/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
A typical NTP monitoring packet
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Internal Commands Control Message Commands Status Words and Kiss Codes System Variables Peer Variables Clock Variables   Synopsis ntpq [-46dinp] [-c command] [host] [&amp;hellip;]
 Description The ntpq utility program is used to monitor NTP daemon ntpd operations and determine performance. It uses the standard NTP mode 6 control message formats defined in Appendix B of the NTPv3 specification RFC 1305.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntptime - read and set kernel time variables</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntptime/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntptime/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
The turtle has been swimming in the kernel.
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Options   Synopsis ntptime [ -chr ] [ -e est_error ] [ -f frequency ] [ -m max_error ] [ -o offset ] [ -s status ] [ -t time_constant]
 Description This program is useful only with special kernels described in the A Kernel Model for Precision Timekeeping page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ntptrace - trace a chain of NTP servers back to the primary source</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntptrace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/ntptrace/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
The rabbit knows the way back.
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Options Bugs   Synopsis ntptrace [ -n ] [ -m maxhosts ] [ server ]
 Description ntptrace is a perl script that uses the ntpq utility program to follow the chain of NTP servers from a given host back to the primary time source. For ntptrace to work properly, each of these servers must implement the NTP Control and Monitoring Protocol specified in RFC 1305 and enable NTP Mode 6 packets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orphan Mode</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/orphan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/orphan/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes an NTP subnet becomes isolated from all UTC sources such as local reference clocks or Internet time servers. In such cases it may be necessary that the subnet servers and clients remain synchronized to a common timescale, not necessarily the UTC timescale. Previously, this function was provided by the local clock driver to simulate a UTC source. A server with this driver could be used to synchronize other hosts in the subnet directly or indirectly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance Metrics</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/stats/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Introduction Statistics Summary Quality of Service   Introduction This page describes several statistics provided in the NTP specification and reference implementation and how they determine the accuracy and error measured during routine and exceptional operation. These statistics provide the following information.
 Nominal estimate of the server clock time relative to the client clock time. This is called clock offset symbolized by the Greek letter θ.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poll Process</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/poll/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/poll/</guid>
      <description>The poll process sends NTP packets at intervals determined by the clock discipline algorithm. The process is designed to provide a sufficient update rate to maximize accuracy while minimizing network overhead. The process is designed to operate over a poll exponent range between 3 (8 s) and 17 (36 hr). The minimum and maximum poll exponent within this range can be set using the minpoll and maxpoll options of the server command, with default 6 (64 s) and 10 (1024 s), respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PPSAPI Interface for Precision Time Signals</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/kernpps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/kernpps/</guid>
      <description>from NBS Special Publication 432, 1979 (out of print)
 Table of Contents  Introduction PPSAPI Application Program Interface   Introduction RFC 2783 describes the PPSAPI application programming interface for external precision time signals, such as the pulse-per-second (PPS) signal generated by some radio clocks and cesium oscillators. The PPSAPI provides a generic capability in the ubiquitous Unix kernel which can be used for a wide variety of measurement applications, including network time synchronization and related experiments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulse-Per-Second (PPS) Signal Interfacing</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/pps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/pps/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
Alice is trying to find the PPS signal connector.
 Table of Contents  Introduction Gadget Box Operating System Support PPS Driver Using the Pulse-per-Second (PPS) Signal   Introduction Most radio clocks are connected using a serial port operating at speeds of 9600 bps. The accuracy using typical timecode formats, where the on-time epoch is indicated by a designated ASCII character such as carriage-return &amp;lt;cr&amp;gt;, is normally limited to 100 μs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick Start</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/quick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/quick/</guid>
      <description>FAX test image for SATNET (1979).
The baby panda was scanned at University College London and used as a FAX test image for a demonstration of the DARPA Atlantic SATNET Program and the first transatlantic Internet connection in 1978. The computing system used for that demonstration was called the Fuzzball. As it happened, this was also the first Internet multimedia presentation and the first to use a predecessor of NTP in regular operation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rate Management and the Kiss-o&#39;-Death Packet</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/rate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/rate/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
Our junior managers and the administrators.
 Table of Contents  Introduction Minimum Headway Time Minimum Average Headway Time The Kiss of Death Packet References   Introduction This page describes the various rate management provisions in NTPv4. Some national time metrology laboratories, including NIST and USNO, use the NTP reference implementation in their very busy public time servers. They operate multiple servers behind load-balancing devices to support aggregate rates up to ten thousand packets per second.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference Clock Audio Drivers</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/audio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/audio/</guid>
      <description>ICOM R-72 shortwave receiver and Sure audio mixer
 Table of Contents  Sound Card Drivers Shortwave Radio Drivers Setup and Debugging Aids   Sound Card Drivers There are some applications in which the computer time can be disciplined to an audio signal, rather than a serial timecode and communications port or special purpose bus peripheral. This is useful in such cases where the audio signal is sent over a telephone circuit, for example, or received directly from a shortwave receiver.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference Clock Commands and Options</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/clockopt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/clockopt/</guid>
      <description>Master Time Facility at the UDel Internet Research Laboratory
 Table of Contents  Reference Clock Addresses Commands and Options   Reference Clock Addresses Unless noted otherwise, further information about these commands is on the Reference Clock Support page.
Reference clocks are identified by a syntactically correct but invalid IP address, in order to distinguish them from ordinary NTP peers. These addresses are of the form 127.127.t.u, where t is an integer denoting the clock type and u indicates the unit number in the range 0-3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reference Clock Support</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/refclock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/refclock/</guid>
      <description>Master Time Facility at the UDel Internet Research Laboratory
 Table of Contents  Introduction Special Considerations List of Reference Clock Drivers   Introduction NTP Version 4 supports almost four dozen satellite, radio and telephone modem reference clocks plus several audio devices for instrumentation signals. A general description of the reference clock support is on this page. Additional information about each reference clock driver can be found via links from this page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Server Commands and Options</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/confopt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/confopt/</guid>
      <description>from Pogo, Walt Kelly
The chicken is getting configuration advice.
 Table of Contents  Server and Peer Addresses Server Commands Server Command Options Auxiliary Commands   Server and Peer Addresses Following is a description of the server configuration commands in NTPv4. There are two classes of commands, configuration commands that configure an association with a remote server, peer or reference clock, and auxiliary commands that specify environment variables that control various related operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Site Map</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/sitemap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/sitemap/</guid>
      <description>Build and Install  Basic Installation Building and Installing the Distribution Build Options Debugging Reference Clock Drivers Quick Start NTP Version 4 Release Notes NTP Debugging Techniques NTP Bug Reporting Procedures   Program Manual Pages  ntpd - Network Time Protocol (NTP) daemon ntpq - standard NTP query program ntpdc - special NTP query program ntpdate - set the date and time via NTP sntp - Simple Network Time Protocol (SNTP) client ntptrace - trace a chain of NTP servers back to the primary source tickadj - set time-related kernel variables ntptime - read and set kernel time variables ntp-keygen - generate public and private keys ntpdsim - Network Time Protocol (NTP) simulator ntp-wait -waits until ntpd is in synchronized state ntp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>sntp - Simple Network Time Protocol (SNTP) Client</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/sntp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/sntp/</guid>
      <description>from Alice&amp;rsquo;s Adventures in Wonderland, Lewis Carroll
S is for snakeoil.
 Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Options Return Value Author   Synopsis sntp [{&amp;ndash;help -?}][{-4 -6}][-a keynum][-b bcaddress][-B bctimeout][-c][-d][-D debug-level][-g delay][-K kodfile][-k keyfile][-l logfile][-M steplimit][-o ntpver][-r][-S][-s][-u uctimeout][&amp;ndash;wait][&amp;ndash;version][address(es)]
 Description This program is a Simple Network Time Protocol (SNTP) client that can be used to query a Network Time Protocol (NTP) server and display the time offset of the system clock relative to the server clock.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Huff-n&#39;-Puff Filter</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/huffpuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/huffpuff/</guid>
      <description>In scenarios where a considerable amount of data are downloaded or uploaded using DSL or telephone modem lines, timekeeping quality can be seriously degraded. This occurs because the traffic volume, and thus the queuing delays, on the upload and download directions of transmission can be very different. In many cases the apparent time errors are so large as to exceed the step threshold and a step correction can occur during and after the data transfer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tickadj - set time-related kernel variables</title>
      <link>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/tickadj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ntp.org/documentation/4.2.8-series/tickadj/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Synopsis Description Command Line Options Files Bugs   Synopsis tickadj [ -Aqs ] [ -a tickadj ] [ -t tick ]
 Description The tickadj program reads, and optionally modifies, several timekeeping-related variables in older kernels that do not have support for precision timekeeping, including HP-UX, SunOS, Ultrix, SGI and probably others. Those machines provide means to patch the kernel /dev/kmem. Newer machines with kernel time support, including Solaris, Tru64, FreeBSD and Linux, should NOT use the program, even if it appears to work, as it will destabilize the kernel time support.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
